Sunny: Hello guys, I'm audible, can you please confirm in the chat, if you can hear me?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, let's start with the session, guys. I hope I am audible.
Sunny: So, give me a moment.
Sunny: Am I visible? Am I audible?
Sunny: Mmm… why this camera is not opening?
Sunny: I think now I'm visible, guys. Yes or no?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, all good. Let's start, let's, begin with the session.
Sunny: So, today, guys, we'll understand couple of more concepts of the langgraph. So, in the previous, class, guys, we understood a couple of concepts of the langgraph, right?
Sunny: So, we understood about the human loop and the other, concept related to the memory and all. Okay, now some, more concepts are the remaining inside the langgraph, so we'll focus over there. And after that, guys, we'll start with the new module. So, three main module is there after the langgraph, after the Agentic AI. So, we'll understand about the MCP guartel and the evaluation, okay?
Sunny: And, right after that, we'll start with the project. Prompt rewriting and all, everything basically is there inside the workflow and all. If you will go and check out our previous workflow, we have written all this thing over there, okay? So, you can, definitely check out all the previous workflow. Got it?
Sunny: So as, we will progress in our project code and all, so there, this, prompt red writing and all, everything will come inside the node itself, right? We can write a different, different functionality in the different, different, functions. Got it?
Sunny: Now, guys, okay, we'll do the deployment in the Azure. Yes, Vikas, I can show you the deployment over the Azure also, means I can take one session. There, basically, we can see how we can deploy any application over the Azure as well. Now, people were having some query. First, let me check out with the community chat.
Sunny: Okay. Now, guys, if you're having any sort of an opening, right, in your company, then please, write it down in the, this one group, itself, so that, like, people can leverage, okay, from here, and, they can, basically avail those opportunities. Got it?
Sunny: Now… can we rename? Yeah, renaming, one, so this I will do, actually, this, week, actually, it was… it was, like, a little busy for me, so I couldn't do that. But it is in my mind, so don't follow those class-related topic, class topic, right? Whatever is, named over there.
Sunny: I would suggest you to follow the, this GitHub topic, okay? I will rename the class topic according to that. Got it? So this is one of the important things, which I will do, definitely.
Sunny: So this week, I did not get much time, that's why I couldn't do that, okay? But guys, don't worry, I'll do that. Now guys, whatever doubts and all you have, definitely you can clarify in the doubt session. Let me check out the previous recording as well. So, there is the previous recording.
Sunny: Yeah, I think recording is up to date. Yes, you are right. So, Generative AI Bootcamp, this is our badge, guys.
Sunny: Yeah, 52 recordings are up-to-date, and the last session I took on 13th of September, and the recording is the up-to-date one. So guys, I'll rename this topic, don't worry, I can, I'll do it, I'll do that, okay? So…
Sunny: It's just, like, a very simple thing. From here, so I'll do that, but just give me more time, maybe 1 or 2 days, okay? I'll rename this topic according to the actual name.
Sunny: Great. So, guys, can we start the session now? Anything, any more thing, which, like, do I need to highlight, or, we can start the session?
Sunny: Sorry, I missed the last two sessions. Do I complete all the Kulkar project? Yes, so at least complete the RAG at the Agentic, at least complete the RAG at the Agentic session before starting the project. Got it, tila?
Sunny: Sir, I'm unable to get the assignment 6. Please let me know which file is this. Assignment 6 is there over the…
Sunny: GitHub, this is the assignment 6. So, here, basically, you have to be implement the MOD-related stuff. So, actually, you will find out some, basically boilerplate code with respect to the memory. You just have to be, like, you just have to do some enhancement on top of this code. Got it, Mary?
Sunny: Is it clear?
Sunny: Okay, great.
Sunny: So, not found, we, we, you just… it will be good also to rename the classes. Yes, Sramam, I'll, I'll do that, okay? Already I,
Sunny: address this doubt. Got it?
Sunny: Yeah. So, guys, just give me a quick thumbs up so that we can start with the session. I just want your quick confirmation.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Great. Now guys, what we have to do, so we have to understand couple of, more concepts of the langgraph, right? So, let me open my notebook, and, there, basically, I capped all the topic, all the stuff, basically. So, let me basically open that. So, here is the notebook, guys. The notebook name is what? subgraph.ipynb.
Sunny: First of all, let me close all the notebook from here.
Sunny: So, yeah, I'm closing it. Now, today is 19th of September.
Sunny: Right, sorry, 19th… yeah, today is 19th of September.
Sunny: So guys, today, basically, we'll discuss the subgraph concept and the different, different orchestrator inside the langgraph, right? So, whenever you are going to design a langgraph, whenever you are going to design an Agentic system, right, or you are going to design any sort of a workflow in the real time, so you are going to be using this kind of orchestrator. So, if you know about this orchestrator, then it will be easy for you to design a workflow, or if someone is writing a code, or let's say.
Sunny: If you're generating a code, from the co-pilot and all, then easily you can, basically understand the concept, if you have understanding of the, different orchestrator and the subgraph and all. Got it?
Sunny: So, now guys, today, basically, we are going to be discussed about the different orchestrator and the subgraph, right? So, this 2 notebook is there. I'll, share with you, Siva, okay?
Sunny: I'll share with you in some time. Okay, so this is going to be a two concept. Definitely, I'll explain to you what is this different orchestrator in the subgraph. I will understand this in a very, very detail.
Sunny: So, here is the code and all everything, guys, with respect to the subgraph. It is well-tested code, and the concept is also very easy. Nothing is there, right? Nothing is very heavy over here. So, I will explain you this entire thing from… with the very simple example. Got it? So, I capped all the details and all here inside the notebook only. Definitely we'll discuss from here.
Sunny: So, guys, whenever we are going to talk about the different orchestrator, right, and whenever we are talking about the subgraph, so there, specifically, we can use the send API of the langgraph.
Sunny: So far, we have understood the different, different, API of the langgraph, like message-ested API, right? Different, different edges, right? Different, different way of creating our notes, right? Now, we have, or even we have understood about the interrupt functionality also, interrupt API also in the previous session, right, with respect to human in loop.
Sunny: Now, guys, what we will do, we'll focus over the new API. That's going to be a send API, right? Which can send the request in a parallel way, okay, to every node, or to every subgraph. Got it? So, let me rename this folder first, guys, and then, basically, I will start with the session.
Sunny: So just give me one more minute, let me rename this folder.
Sunny: So… memory management, got it. So, memory management, extended. Human in loop, I think this I discussed in the previous class.
Sunny: So, let me crop the… let me crop this human in lieu from here.
Sunny: Okay, and then, guys, I can…
Sunny: write it over here. So, the concept name is going to be…
Sunny: Human in low. Okay, in the previous session itself, I discussed this one. Now, subgraph, different workflow orchestrators. Let me crop this name from here, because this is going to be agent of today's session. Got it?
Sunny: So, here what I can do, guys, I can, keep this particular topic, subgraph, different, and the different workflow orchest data. Multientic flow, we'll discuss in the next class, guys. We'll see what is a multi-entic flow.
Sunny: So, human loop is fine, just a second.
Sunny: So this is subgraph, right?
Sunny: So, from here, I can take this multi-agentic flow.
Sunny: I hope this is clear. Now, let's do one thing, guys.
Sunny: Let me close it for this, okay, I think now I can do it. Okay, this is done.
Sunny: Now I can write this particular name.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: multi-agentic flow. Now, let me keep the correct notebook also in every folder.
Sunny: So, yeah, notebook is a multientic flow, so this we'll discuss in tomorrow's session. And, here, guys, the notebook related to the different orchestrator and the subgraph, right? Now, everything is set, I think, this, GitHub folder is having the correct name.
Sunny: Okay, so right now, basically, you can follow this particular name, right? Okay, so each and every lecture having their respective name. Now, guys, I'm committing all the changes, to the GitHub, so I'm going to open it inside the VS Code again.
Sunny: code dot, and now let me, basically…
Sunny: Push it. Now guys, are you getting any background noise from mine? I don't think so. Any background noise?
Sunny: Can you please confirm? I don't think so. Is there any background noise?
Sunny: I think a little bit might be there because some program is going on, right? The Ganesha program in my society. So maybe some noise is coming from there itself. So guys, give me a moment. Let me close the window, okay? Then, please confirm, whether you're getting or not, right? So, give me a moment. I'm closing my window, right?
Sunny: Yeah, now, guys, it is better.
Sunny: I think now it is better, right? So my room window was open, and I think, the voice… the background voice, actually, it was coming from there itself, right?
Sunny: Okay, so guys, I'm giving you all the changes,
Sunny: Just give me a moment. So this rough, actually, I can mention inside the git ignore, because it is not required to me right now.
Sunny: R-O-U-G-H. R-O-U-G-H. Okay.
Sunny: So, now this 1, 2, 3, 4, these changes are there. So, let me add it, and then I can commit it. So, here is code updated. Okay? Now, commit and push, guys. So, once you got the code, just give me quick confirmation.
Sunny: Sir, we got a code, now, we can proceed.
Sunny: just check out, guys, just check with the GitHub, and please let me know if the code is there. Take a code in your local, so that you can refer while you are learning.
Sunny: Understood?
Sunny: Even I can refresh it, so… just give me a moment, I can refresh.
Sunny: Yeah, code is there, guys. All the updated code is there. Please check it out now.
Sunny: Do it, guys, fast. I'm giving you one more of time. Please check the entire code and all everything.
Sunny: Yeah, got the code, guys, yes or no?
Sunny: Give me a quick thumbs up so that we can start.
Sunny: Yeah? Okay, great.
Sunny: Basically, I kept the explanation inside the notebook itself. So, this, explanation, basically, it will help you, okay, to understand the code flow, to understand about the concept.
Sunny: So, even though you are revising in a standalone mode, let's say you don't want to watch the session and you want to revise a concept, so definitely you can follow this particular notebook, okay? Or else you can provide this notebook to the co-pilot, to the Claw. Chatt GPT, right? And you can understand the entire workflow from there itself. Got it, guys?
Sunny: But yeah, definitely we'll discuss in the live class also, but yeah, I'm just giving you some suggestions at how you can basically do the revision. Let's say if you're going in an interview, and let's say if you wanted to build something, right, using this concept.
Sunny: then how you can utilize that. Now guys, what I'm doing, so let's understand the concept, okay? So, I'm going to open my Blackboard, and there, basically, I'll…
Sunny: Explain the concept, right? So, here, guys, I'll explain the concept of the subgraph, so just confirm if you can see my blackboard, guys.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Yes, Renjan, you can use the Olama, that is completely fine. You can use the Olama.
Sunny: Okay, instead of the OpenAI.
Sunny: Sir, I have, missed your Git link, please share in the chat.
Sunny: I shared it multiple times.
Sunny: But yeah, if you're asking, then I can share it again.
Sunny: Okay? So, guys, see, what is the concept of the subgraph? So, let me open a new notebook.
Sunny: And, they'll basically, I'll explain you.
Sunny: So, this concept was related to…
Sunny: Let me check, guys, what I have explained over here.
Sunny: Okay, so here, basically, we understood about the memory.
Sunny: So, the title is the memory. I already shared this file, so you can check out, in the GitHub, guys, you will find out these entire notes and all everything. Got it?
Sunny: Now guys, the next concept is going to be different orchestrator in the subgraph. So first, we'll start, from the subgraph, okay? So let me write over here, subgraph.
Sunny: Okay? Now, what is the meaning of the subgraph? Now, before starting with the subgraph, guys, we'll have to understand about a graph.
Sunny: Okay? Now, what's a graph, guys? So, graph is nothing. It's a collection of the
Sunny: It's a collection of the nodes and edges.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Collection of what? Collection of the… Nodes and edges.
Sunny: So we have a different, different nodes and different, different edges, correct? So here, what I can do, I can, write a note, right? Let's say this is my first node, which is containing a first functionality. This is my another node, guys, okay? And then there's my another node. Now, this node actually is connected to each other.
Sunny: Okay? This node actually is connected to each other. So this is called what guy? This is called a graph.
Sunny: This is what?
Sunny: This is my graph.
Sunny: Or, in short, I can say the workflow.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Now, here itself, basically, we are going to be implement the Agentic.
Sunny: flow.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Using the graph concept only, we are going to be implementing the Agentic flow. Now, what is this node, guys? If we're talking about the node, this particular node.
Sunny: So this node is nothing, let's say this is my node, right? N1.
Sunny: This is my AND2.
Sunny: And this is my N3.
Sunny: So this nodes is nothing, it's a functionality.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Agree guys, yes or no?
Sunny: So, these nodes are nothing. These nodes, actually, it's a functionality, right? We can keep any sort of a functionality inside this node, and then what we can do, we can connect to these nodes to each other. Now, this is what, guys? This is my address.
Sunny: Okay? Edge is basically, it's a connectivity between the nodes.
Sunny: Making sense to all of you? Yes or no?
Sunny: Is this thing making sense? Okay. Now, what is a subgraph, guys? So, subgraph is nothing. So, right, subgraph, basically, it's a graph, okay, which we can append inside any parent graph. So, here, guys, see, I have a graph, okay? Now, let's say this is my graph, one of the graph.
Sunny: This is the notes.
Sunny: Okay? And between the nodes, we have a connectivity, right?
Sunny: So, let's say this is my node 1.
Sunny: This is my node 2, and this is my Node 3.
Sunny: So this node is nothing… sorry, this is nothing.
Sunny: This is what, guys? This is my graph.
Sunny: Okay, this is my graph. Now, here is my edges.
Sunny: So, edge 1.
Sunny: Edge 2.
Sunny: Okay? So this is what… this is my one of the graphs.
Sunny: Now, let's suppose we have one more graph.
Sunny: So here, I'm going to design one more graph, guys.
Sunny: So, let's say this is my one graph.
Sunny: One more graph, guys. This one, this one, and this one, okay?
Sunny: This one, this one, and this one.
Sunny: Now, how many nodes are there inside the graph?
Sunny: So inside this particular graph, we have 4 nodes. As you can see, how many nodes are there?
Sunny: So inside this particular graph, we have 4 nodes.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And the node, specifically, it's connected to each other. Node 1.
Sunny: Note 2.
Sunny: Note 3.
Sunny: And Note 4.
Sunny: Right? So, how many, graphs we have? So, we have… sorry, how many nodes we have? So, we have 4 nodes, right? Now guys, this is what is my edges. So, here is my edge 1.
Sunny: This is my H2.
Sunny: And here is my edge 3.
Sunny: So inside the notes, what we are going to write, guys, we are going to be write the functional.
Sunny: So let me write some, let me define… write over here functions, right?
Sunny: So there's malfunctions.
Sunny: Function 1, function 2, Now, this is about this map function.
Sunny: 3, and this is what is my function for.
Sunny: Okay? So this is my second, third, and fourth. Now, inside this particular function, we can write anything, any sort of a functionality, whatever you wanted to write, right? You can write that…
Sunny: Okay, so this is what, this is my one of the graphs. So, here, guys, I'm saying…
Sunny: This is my… another graph.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Now, what's the concept of a subgraph, guys? So, the concept of the subgraph is very easy. So, this particular graph, this… the first graph which you can see, this one.
Sunny: this particular graph, the first graph which you can see, okay. Now, this particular graph, you can ingest inside the second graph. This is my first graph.
Sunny: And this is what is my second graph.
Sunny: Graph 2.
Sunny: Now, this graph, too, actually, let's say I'm seeing this is my parent graph.
Sunny: This graph, too, is what? It is my parent graph. Now, inside this graph too, what I can do, I can ingest the graph first, okay? So, let's say I'm picking up this particular node, this particular node.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And inside this particular node, inside this particular function, I'm ingesting this graph1.
Sunny: This graph one.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: This particular gap I'm ingesting.
Sunny: Right? So now this graph 1, actually, this graph 1, it will become… subgraph… It will become subgraph.
Sunny: of… This parent graph.
Sunny: Getting my point, guys? Yes or no? Is it getting clear to all of you? What is a subgraph? So, any of the graph we can ingest as a node in any parent graph.
Sunny: Okay, so that is called a subgraph. The name itself is a self-explanatory.
Sunny: The name itself is a self-explanatory, right? So what's the meaning of the subgraph? Subgraph, basically, it's a graph which is a part of any parent graph.
Sunny: Okay? Which is what, guys? Which is a part of the parent graph. So tell me, guys, is this clear? How many of you are able to understand? Then I'll show you the practical. Tell me first.
Sunny: Clear?
Sunny: If you have any sort of a doubt, you can ask me.
Sunny: Sir, can you explain me with any real-world example for easy understanding? Yes, I have a real-world example. I capped it inside the code itself. I'll explain you that. Got it? Ganesh?
Sunny: So, can graph 1 be a parent graph?
Sunny: Grav… can graph 1 could be a parent graph, yes. If you are using… if you are using any other graph, right, inside any of the nodes, so that is also called a parent graph, but…
Sunny: That is also called the parent graph. Now, this parent graph, if you're going to be used inside this particular graph, the final graph, right? So, ultimately, this will become the parent graph, okay? So, we can say this is the sub-parent graph.
Sunny: We can say this is the sub-parent graph.
Sunny: What is E1 and E2 Abhi? So, we are going to be complete the langgraph. Now you are asking this thing, Abhi?
Sunny: Is it an expected one?
Sunny: Even when it is an edges, okay? That means you're not revising the concept, you're not going through with the notebook and all.
Sunny: please, go through with the material at least, and try to run some example by your end. Got it?
Sunny: Parent graph is a graph one, right? No, parent is this one.
Sunny: This is the parent graph, and this graph 1, right, is a part of the parent-parent graph. So, graph 1 is called the subgraph of the parent graph, the graph 2. Got it? Don't be confused, Ranjith, it's a very simple concept, okay?
Sunny: how graph and the Agentic AI both are different between each other, with the graph itself, with the graph flow only, we are going to be achieving the Agentic AI, okay? So whether we can achieve in the LLM, in the tool calling manner, or we can segregate the entire flow into the nodes and the edges. Everything we have discussed in the previous session, Anil
Sunny: Got it? Please let us know the benefit in terms of application. Yes, Pi Avarthra, I'll discuss the benefit in terms of the application, you will understand. Is the state shared between the parent graph and the subgraph? Yes. State will be shared.
Sunny: Graph 1 is start from node 2 of the graph? Yes, we can compile it separately, then we… it can be a part of it, and then whenever you are going to… whenever we are going to be invoking the final parent graph, according to that, the final call would be there, okay? And inside the parent graph itself, this graph 1 will be invoked. Got it?
Sunny: Great. So, guys, let's understand, with the example. With that, your understanding will be more clear.
Sunny: So, what I'm doing…
Sunny: Great. So, guys, can you see this particular notebook? The code is visible to all of you.
Sunny: Yes, we should understand the Agent AKI with the langgraph itself. It is easy for us, okay? And most of the time, it is being used in the industry. Got it, Vikas?
Sunny: Okay, so, guys, I think you can see the notebook. Now, inside the notebook, you can see, so let me start from here itself, okay? So, we have all the theory and all, just like, it's a very, basically, basic theory, okay? So, once you will read all this stuff, you will get a clear-cut understanding.
Sunny: So, let's move to the code, guys. So, I hope this import statement is visible.
Sunny: So, here, guys, what we are doing, we are going to be import, this unnotated type, typed it, okay? Operator, state graph, start and, and send. Now, where all these things are being used, so I'll show you that in some time. I hope, guys, you are familiar with all this import statement.
Sunny: Yes. Have you seen this imported statement in our previous code as well?
Sunny: If you are following to me very closely, then I hope you have seen all this stuff in the previous code as well. Now guys, we have one method, so show graph, so this, basically, this, graph, this method, it will give you the, detailed, basically overview of the graph, okay?
Sunny: detailed understanding of the graph, right? So, what is happening?
Sunny: Okay, now guys, the actual code is going to be start from here, this one. So, we have one class. So, what does this, guys, tell me? This is my schema.
Sunny: Okay, this is what, guys? This is my schema. Okay, or we can say this is my state. So, inside this schema, inside this state, we have product, quantity, inventory, status, total price, and the final response. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So, we have all these values, and now we have a product catalog. You can think this is… this value actually is coming from the databases. So, as of now, I just capped it inside the simple dictionary, but in a real time, this might come from the real-time storage. Got it, guys?
Sunny: Good.
Sunny: Yes or no? Tell me.
Sunny: So, this particular value, basically, it might come from the… it might come from where this particular value, actually, it might come from the databases, okay?
Sunny: Now, here, I have kept the definition of the subgraph as well, so you can see what it does. So, the parent graph validates an order, a nested graph check inventory, and then calculates the price.
Sunny: The parent can then create the final response, okay?
Sunny: Why it is a subgraph? So, order subgraph is a compiled separately, added to the parent as an order processing, right? Because both graphs, use order state, and state value pass between them automatically.
Sunny: So, what we are doing, guys, over here, inside this particular use case, so inside this particular use case, basically, we have created one inventory management system, okay? Do you understand the inventory management system? So, there, what we are doing, so, basically.
Sunny: We are… we are, like, validating the order, right?
Sunny: We are checking it in our inventory, right? What is the price and all the… and the other detail of it, and then, basically, we are going to be generate the final response, okay? So, inside this inventory management system, what we can do, we can, basically create a separate, separate functionality as a separate, separate graph.
Sunny: Okay? So, one of the functionality, basically, we have created is a separate graph, and then, that functionality, I'm going to be in just inside the parent graph. Got it, guys?
Sunny: Yes or no? I want everyone's yes if you are getting them, okay? That's why, again and again, I'm asking. Otherwise, I can simply go ahead, okay, with the entire theory and the practical. So guys, see, nested graph, what it is doing, it is going to be check the inventory and calculating the price, okay?
Sunny: So once I will, once I will basically execute it, then you will get the better understanding.
Sunny: So, we have one, schema. We can create this schema using the typed date, we can create this schema using the base class, right? The, typical Pyntic object, okay?
Sunny: We can create in a both way, and I think we understood the both thing in the previous classes. So we have a product, we have a quantity, we have an inventory status, total price of it, and the final response. So, these particular things are flowing inside the entire graph, okay? This particular value.
Sunny: Now, this product catalog, you can think. This one, you can think as a database, okay? So, as of now, I just kept, detail of the keyboard and the mouse. So, keyboard is the stock in 5. It is in a stock, the value is 5.
Sunny: This is a unit price, and mouse, the stock is 10, and it is in a unit price, okay?
Sunny: So, here, guys, what we are going to do, so we are going to be create a subgraph first. So, what the subgraph is doing? So, subgraph, basically, it's going to be check the inventory, okay? It's going to be check the inventory, and then it's going to be calculate the price.
Sunny: Okay? So, this two things is being done by the subgraph. So, here is a functionality of the subgraph, guys. So, we have this, we have this, we have this check inventory, okay? Let me show you the code in the separate cell.
Sunny: And then, guys, the second one is going to be a calculate price. So, whenever we are passing input inside the langgraph, so tell me, guys, in which form we are going to be passing the input in the langgraph.
Sunny: So, we're going to be passed the input in the form of estate, okay? So, we are passing the state. Now, from the state, guys, we are taking the product, and the product detail, basically, we are gathering from the product catalog. So, is it clear, guys, this one?
Sunny: Is this part clear? This one, this particular line? It's very easy to understand, nothing is there, right?
Sunny: Then, guys, what we are checking? So, we are checking product is stock, okay? And the quantity of it, right? If it is greater than and equal to, then we are saying it is available.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no? And then what we are going to do, we are going to be written the inventory status. Okay, if it is available, then we are saying it is available. If it is not available, we are saying it is not available. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So, this is what, this is my check inventory. Then, we have a different method, so calculating the price. So, here we are passing the state. Now, from the state, guys, what we are checking…
Sunny: So, from the state, guys, we are going to be checking the inventory status. So, this inventory status, we are passing away from here, and if it is not equal to available, then we are returning the zero as a price.
Sunny: Okay? Otherwise, guys, what we are saying, if, if it is not equal to available, means it is available, right? So here, what we are doing, so with respect to the product, we are going to be fetch the unit price, okay, from the product catalog. So this is what, guys, this is the unit price, okay? And then, guys, we are going to be written the…
Sunny: total price, so it's whatever quantity user is asking, we are just going to be multiply that particular quantity with the unit price, so that's going to be what? That's going to be our final price. So is this functionality clear, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: From the inventory, from our warehouse, guys, we are going to be check, okay, whether the product is available or not. If it is available, guys, we are just giving the final price of that.
Sunny: If this part is clear, please let me know.
Sunny: Yes, the simple Python function only will be used inside the langgraph nodes. Okay, we can convert into the langgraph node Amit.
Sunny: If you've ever seen the langgraph code in the previous classes, we are doing the same thing over there, okay? So now, guys, what we are doing, we are going to be create the subgraph, okay? Guys, this is my graph.
Sunny: Okay, so this particular graph, we are going to be in just our parent graph, so that's why we are calling it as a subgraph. Got it? So, how we can prepare the subgraph, guys, means this particular graph. So, first, guys, we'll call this state graph method, or sometimes we call it as a state graph API, okay? So, this is my…
Sunny: Name. Okay, this is the name. Order subgraph builder. So first, guys, let me select the kernel, so at least we can execute it, we can execute the code, and then finally we can look into the response. So, I'm going to be, execute the code from starting. So, this is running, this is fine. We are going to define the, like,
Sunny: Schema, okay? The state, basically. So, check inventory and calculate price. Let's create a graph. So, here, basically, what is there? So, order subgraph builder. So, this is the name which I'm providing to this particular object, okay? Now, here we are going to be at the node.
Sunny: So, how many nodes we have right now, guys? Tell me. So, we have two nodes. The first is a check inventory node, and the second is what? Calculate price node. Got it, guys?
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, what we are doing, we are going to be at the edges, okay? So, start to check inventory, then check inventory to calculate price, and then calculate price to end. So, this is what, guys, this is my one graph, okay? So, here, guys, what I can do, I can simply execute it.
Sunny: And then we can compile that particular graph. So, here is my…
Sunny: compilation process. So once I learn it, guys, so my, order subgraph is ready.
Sunny: So this, did you understand, guys? I just given the… I just given this, variable name in such a way, so that you can understand. It's just a graph right now, which we are going to be ingesting any, parent graph, so that it will become the subgraph. Got it, guys? Yes or no? Tell me.
Sunny: Yes, we can draw the image without calling the draw as well. Okay, that is also one more way. So, how's the understanding so far?
Sunny: May I know in the chat? I think everyone is getting this simple example. So, someone was asking about the real-time example, and I give all the… and I given the real-time example, okay? So, let's, create the parent graph now. So, let's, do one thing, guys. Let's create the parent graph.
Sunny: Estate means node. Node. Node means function, and state means the input we are passing throughout the function, throughout the nodes. Got it, Asutosh? So, this acts as an abstract class in a real time.
Sunny: yes, you can say in that way, if you are using it inside the, parent graph, okay? So.
Sunny: So, as a developer, you know about that, you know about that functionality, right? So, it will not be abstract for you. You know about all the subgraph and all, got it?
Sunny: Yes, you can say state is equal to session, okay? This is one more name of the state, correct, which is flowing throughout the different, different nodes, which is flowing throughout the entire workflow. Got it?
Sunny: Okay. Is there a method or process to know when to create a subgraph whenever you wanted to delegate the functionality?
Sunny: Right? So if you have a bigger system, and inside the bigger system, if you wanted to delegate the functionality, at that time, you are going to be create a subgraph. It's just, like, on your engineering knowledge, right? How well you know about the subgraph, how well you know about the Agentic flow, how well you know about the langgraph system.
Sunny: Getting my point?
Sunny: Yes or no? So, you not even required to create a subgraph for this particular example.
Sunny: Right? Not even required for creating a subgraph. Without that also, we can create the simple graph, and we can run our flow, right? But when the system is bigger, let's say we are going to be implementing this particular functionality into the real time.
Sunny: At that time, guys, what we can do, we can delegate the functionality into the smallest small graph, and then we can call that particular functionality from one parent graph. Got it, guys? Yes or no? So that, this workflow will be easy to maintain. Let's say if I'm asking to you, okay, can you please check the…
Sunny: Can you please check this inventory management system? You will simply go to… you will simply go and check the inventory management system graph.
Sunny: Let's say if you are going to be checking the invoice processing, right? So, simply, you can check out the invoice processing. Let's say if I'm asking to you, can you check the final processing, okay, of the output, you can simply look into that particular graph. So, we are going to be delegate word, we are going to be delegate the functionality over here, that's it, okay?
Sunny: Okay, so how's the understanding? I think the understanding is now very good. So, let's create one, a parent graph. So, here, guys, we have one functionality. Let's look into this particular functionality.
Sunny: So, here, this is the valid request, okay? The function name is what? Valid request. So, it will take as a… it will take input as a state, okay? Now, here we are, checking the product, right? If the product is not there inside the product catalog, we are saying it's an unknown product.
Sunny: And we cannot provide you any sort of a detail about it.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, let's say if the product quantity, okay, the quantity of the product is less than zero, or less than equal to zero, right? Then we are saying quantity must be greater than the zero. So if, the request is coming in such a way, then guys, we are going to be raise the error over here.
Sunny: Got it? It's very easy to… easy functionality. Then, what is there, guys? So, create final response. So, how we can create a final response? So, over here, guys, what we will do, we'll take a state, okay?
Sunny: From the state, we are checking the available state. Okay, if it is available, guys, then the response, we are going to be framed in such a way. So, we have a quantity.
Sunny: Of the product, okay, which is ordered, and this is the final price, okay? And otherwise, guys, if it is not available, then we are saying order not place, quantity, and the product is not available, right? And then we are going to be written the final response. So that's it, guys, so this is what, guys, this is my final response.
Sunny: Now, let me create the fi- let me create the final flow, okay?
Sunny: So, at the first place, what will happen, guys? So, this is my final graph, right? So, we have created the order builder now, okay? This is my parent graph. Now, here, guys, what we have? So, order builder, add node. So, this is my valid request, and the
Sunny: subgraph node, okay, and then you can see the final response. So what we are doing, guys, over here, we are going to be add the previous graph as a node. So let me add it over here.
Sunny: So this is what, guys, tell me, this one. So this is my valid request. This valid request is nothing, it is this particular functionality, this one. But if we're talking about this one, this node, order, order subgraph, right? So, from where it is coming, guys, let me show you.
Sunny: So, this is my order subgraph.
Sunny: This is a complete graph, okay, which we have created over here.
Sunny: For calculating what? For calculating the inventory price, okay? So, let me keep it over here, this order processing. So, let me, basically add it inside the node. Now, we have one more node over here. So, guys, here you can see we have one more node, this one, final response one.
Sunny: So this final response is this one. Got it, guys? So, this validate request and this create final response is two, additional functionality which I created as a part of the parent graph, and rest of the functionality is coming from our subgraph, okay, from the previous graph, which we have ingested over here. Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: Now, we are going to recreate the final edge.
Sunny: So we have start, okay, then it will go to the validate request. Then validate request, it will pass to the order processing, which is my one of the graph only.
Sunny: Now, order processing, basically, it is passing the output to the final response, so it will build the final response, and after that, the process is going to be end, okay? So, this is what this is my final graph, guys. Now, if I'm going to be executed, so, see, before the execution will have to be compiled.
Sunny: So I have compiled it. Okay, so I think I have not executed something. Let me check it out over here.
Sunny: So, this is my state graph, this is my node, node, node, this is done. Then, my order graph is ready, okay? So, guys, my order graph is ready. Now, if I will execute it, see, you will find out the complete graph. Now, this is my one of the nodes, this is my one of the nodes. Now, tell me, guys, what is this? This one?
Sunny: This one?
Sunny: What is this, guys? Tell me.
Sunny: This is my… one of the subgraph.
Sunny: Okay, so we can say… This is my… one of the… subgraph
Sunny: So guys, if you're doing it in a real time.
Sunny: And the application is very, very huge.
Sunny: let's say we have to manage this inventory… manage… inventory system in the real time. Now, so many processes going all together.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: so many processes going all together. So, with respect to every sort of a process, You can create the…
Sunny: subgraph.
Sunny: Okay? Then you will be having one final graph.
Sunny: Inside that final graph, basically, you can append all these processes.
Sunny: Understood, guys? Yes or no? Tell me. So, what is a diff… what is a U… what is the benefit of creating this subgraph, guys?
Sunny: So every process will be the isolated one. If you wanted to execute in a parallel, you can execute in a parallel also. And every, basically, every sort of a functionality is going to be delegated to a different, different graph. So the final graph, basically, it's not going to be a very, very complex
Sunny: So the final graph, basically, it's not going to be a very, very complex…
Sunny: Okay, is it getting clear? If it is clear, just give me a quick thumbs up so that we can proceed.
Sunny: Yeah, you can think in such a way, like, it's a microservices, right?
Sunny: But that, we use in a different context.
Sunny: Abhijkji, you can edit the parent graph also. You can edit… you can add everything in the parent graph itself, right? But if we have a use case, right, where we have so many processes, like I have experienced this, inventory management, or any sort of a process in any industry, right?
Sunny: So, there, this subgraph will be required. I can give you one more example. So, I was working on one manufacturing system.
Sunny: Okay? So this manufacturing system, basically, it was related to the medicines. You know about the medicines.
Sunny: Right? Now, whenever we are going to be installing this manufacturing system, so we have lots of documents.
Sunny: to assess this manufacturing system, this one, okay? So I created one workflow.
Sunny: I created one workflow from starting to end.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: From starting to end, right? And inside this workflow, basically, I have to assess the… I have to assess what? I have to assess the different, different document, okay? I have to validate the different, different document.
Sunny: Now, we're talking about this manufacturing setup, right? So, inside this manufacturing setup, we can have a different, different functionality, right? So, let's say some installation-related functionality, some material-related functionality.
Sunny: Okay, some packaging-related functionality. And with respect to, with respect to this particular functionality, we have a document.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: We have a document. Now, what we have to do, we have to assess this particular document.
Sunny: So what we can do, guys, with respect to every sort of a document, We can create our subgraph.
Sunny: Right? Let's say subgraph 1, subgraph 2, subgraph 3, right? And we can ingest in our final.
Sunny: workflow.
Sunny: Now, let's say if I just have to be, like, modify something inside this installation workflow, right? To assessment of this installation workflow, I can simply go and check over here only why I need to touch this two things.
Sunny: why I need to touch these two things. Simply, I can do some modification over here itself. Getting my point, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: So, likewise, basically, we can design our system.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: you will have to decide, Kamal, with your knowledge, okay, with your expertise, right? I'm not coming over there to tell you, okay, use this functionality as a subgraph.
Sunny: You will have to put your own, brainstorming over there, and you have… you will have to design the system as a…
Sunny: AI engineer. Got it? Yes or no? Kumar?
Sunny: Okay, yes, we have compiled both of the things.
Sunny: We have come by both of the things.
Sunny: So, I think I have given you the enough explanation, and this is one of the real-time examples. I think someone is asking, sir, can you give me the real-time, explanation? So, I can keep the same graph, where, guys, over the notebook itself, and whenever you are going through with any of the, like, real-time example, you can consider this one.
Sunny: Okay, so validate the request, order processing, and the final response. Now, let's execute this graph, and let's see how we are getting the result. Now, guys, I have created one more function, just to give you the complete detail, okay, of the graph.
Sunny: It is not a visualization of that, so here you can see the visualization of the graph, this one. Now, this is just a…
Sunny: granular level, basically detail of the graph, okay? What is happening inside the graph, you will get everything over here. So, once I'll execute this function, sowGraph, and I'll pass this particular parameter, like, true, XRUE, okay, along with my graph.
Sunny: Then you will see the complete detail of the graph. So, here you can see the complete detail of the graph, guys. So, we have a start, this is my first note, then it is validating the request, then final response. Okay, then it's going to be end up process, right?
Sunny: Now, start validating the request. Now, this particular thing is going where? It is going to the order processing, okay? So, what this order processing is doing, so it is going to be calculating the pricing, and it's giving to the final response, right? Now, this validate request, it is going to the order processing, and then it is checking the inventory, right? So.
Sunny: validate request.
Sunny: Okay, order processing, this is my one of the graphs. Now it is going to the check inventory, right? And then it's coming to the final response. Now, this is the detail of the subgraph. So, order processing, check inventory, right? Order processing, calculating price. Order processing, check inventory, right?
Sunny: And then, order processing, calculating graph. Means it is kind of the, like, the low-level detail of the functionality which we have returned. So just by seeing this, like, the, X-ray of the graph, right, you can understand what is happening inside the actual system.
Sunny: Okay, just by looking into this entire detail, you can understand what is happening inside the actual system. If in a real time your graph is going to be bigger, right, or so, like, huge graph, and you are not able to understand what is happening inside.
Sunny: So you can take a help of this particular functionality, where you will be able to understand what is there inside this, what is there inside this particular workflow. Got it? Is it getting clear?
Sunny: Now, guys, what we can do, we can test out this particular workflow. So, here, guys, my function, run order workflow. So, this is my final graph, where we are invoking with the product name and the quantity, and let's see what result I'm getting. Okay, so if I'm going to be executed…
Sunny: Now, after the execution, see, here, basically, you will find out the details. So, validating request, checking inventory, calculating price, true keyword order, and the total price is 1000 rupees. We can check out with any sort of, other details, so…
Sunny: Here, guys, what I'm doing. In this function, I am mentioning some other detail. Now, instead of the keyword, guys, let's say I'm going to mention the monitor.
Sunny: Now, let's say the monitor quantity is 5.
Sunny: So, tell me, guys, what I'll be getting over here if I'm going to be executed, this one.
Sunny: what I'll be getting over here if I'm going to be executed.
Sunny: So if I'm going to be executed, guys, I'll be getting over here.
Sunny: unknown product monitor, okay? During task with name, validate request ID. So this task is going to be fail over here, because we are raising the error, guys, okay? We are raising the error, and because of that, guys, we are getting this particular error over here.
Sunny: We can basically log the error also, we can simply showcase over the terminal also, or we can create the user-friendly error also. That is also fine. Got it?
Sunny: Now guys, what we can do, we can check out with the other, product also. So, in our database, okay, so what I can do, I can write some other name.
Sunny: Let's say… Where is my product catalog?
Sunny: What is this product catalog? Can anyone tell me what is this?
Sunny: What is this one?
Sunny: So this is the… this is… this is a database, actually. It's not a schema. Here, your database, it's not a schema. This is our schema.
Sunny: It's our database. Okay, this one. Why you are saying it's a schema?
Sunny: So every sort of a detail is coming from here. Actually, in a real time, you will be managing this, product… you will be managing this inventory system na, right? You will be holding the details somewhere, na? Guys, yes or no?
Sunny: Right? You will be holding the details somewhere. So, yeah, so that is what? That's a database. As of now, I just created a simple dictionary only, but in the real time, it would be a database, okay? So, what I can do, guys, I can simply keep the product name over here, let's say keyboard.
Sunny: And I'm checking the quantity, let's say the quantity is the 50. Okay, now here, if I'll execute it, now see, what will be coming. I just need to execute this function, so this is the…
Sunny: Call, okay? So, if I'm going to be executed, now sleep. So, we're getting the… we are getting the answer, because this was available inside our system, okay? So, product is keyboard, quantity is 50.
Sunny: Inventory status unavailable, total price is zero. And final response, order not place, 50 keyboard are not available. How many keyboard is available? Let's see if we are running it, with the… how many, basically…
Sunny: Keyboard, let's say.
Sunny: 2 keyboard, okay? If I'm going to be executed with a 2 keyboard, let's, let's execute this particular function. Let's see the result.
Sunny: So, here, guys, you can see.
Sunny: validate request, checking inventory, calculating price, and 2 keyboard order, the total price is 1000 rupees. So, is it getting, clear, guys, how to, how to mount this subgraph? How to mount this subgraph inside your actual parent graph? If this part is getting clear, just let me know, because…
Sunny: It is very easy to understand. Nothing is there.
Sunny: You can try this one. If parent, not have state parent state in the child, but it should have the shared state, okay? Whatever example we are going to be built, we are going to be built around the shared state, okay? Inside the subgraph. Got it? Otherwise, it will not be able to maintain the entire flow.
Sunny: Do you want the revision of it? I can give you the quick revision, but the flow and the flow and the concept is very, very simple.
Sunny: So, what we were trying to understand, we were trying to understand about the subgraph.
Sunny: So guys, here we have created one graph.
Sunny: Now here, guys, we have created one more graph.
Sunny: Okay? Now, this graph we are calling as a parent graph.
Sunny: And this graph, we are calling as a…
Sunny: subgraph. Now, can anyone tell me why it is a parent graph and why it is a subgraph? This one? Both are the graph only, right? Why it is a parent graph and why it is a subgraph?
Sunny: Tell me, tell me, tell me fast, guys, tell me fast.
Sunny: Very easy, right? It is very easy. Why you're taking this much of time?
Sunny: Where is the graph? This is the graph, guys, this one.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: Okay, let me keep it over here.
Sunny: So, is this my sub… is this my graph? This is my graph, no, this one.
Sunny: I hope this is clear, right?
Sunny: So this is what, guys, this is my graph. This one.
Sunny: So this particular graph is called the… this particular graph is called the subgraph.
Sunny: Okay? So instead of the one big graph, what we can do, we can divide our functionality to the multiple subgraph.
Sunny: So, is this concept clear, just by looking into this particular architecture?
Sunny: I shared the code, you can definitely check out. You can look into the code, okay? Even I explained you that.
Sunny: Again, I will come to the different example.
Sunny: If I'm missing any sort of a question, guys, you can ask me in a doubt session. From last 6 months, I'm repeating the same thing.
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: Okay, now, where we should use the subgraph versus function calling? See, this kind of functionality, we cannot compile into the one single function.
Sunny: Okay? We have to be divided into the multiple functions.
Sunny: the functionality could be a complex one, right? So we cannot compile everything inside the single node, single function. We cannot write everything inside the single function. We are basically to break down that functionality, right? So we can use the graph, and we can append inside one particular graph. Got it? Yes or no, Krish?
Sunny: So, single function, use whenever you have a simple functionality. Use the subgraph, break down the functionality into the multiple graph whenever you have a different, different, sorry, whenever you have a complex functionality, okay?
Sunny: So, let's do one thing, guys, let's understand the concept of the parallel processing also. So, here the concept is basically what we can do. So, let's suppose this is my one of the graphs.
Sunny: This is Maya.
Sunny: One of the graph guys, this one.
Sunny: So we are saying this graph is a parent graph.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So I'm saying this is a… parent graph.
Sunny: Okay? So this is what? This is what? This is my parent graph, right? Now, let's say this is my one node.
Sunny: Let's say we have one more node over here.
Sunny: Let's say we have one more node.
Sunny: And let's say… one more nome. This one.
Sunny: Let's suppose, guys, this is what this is my…
Sunny: This particular node, or what? This particular node is my… subgraph.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This is mine.
Sunny: subgraph 1.
Sunny: And this particular node is what? This particular node is mine.
Sunny: subgraph 2.
Sunny: Got it, guys. So, guys, instead of connecting this subgraph parallelly.
Sunny: Sorry, instead of connecting the subgraph, sequentially, Okay. C…
Sunny: Sequentially, sequence Q U A QU ATIUN. Sequentially.
Sunny: Okay. C-s-c-q-u-a-t-i-o double L. Okay, so sometime now, whenever you're writing a spelling.
Sunny: Sequentially, right? So instead of running this particular graph sequentially, I wanted to run it, I wanted to execute it parallelly.
Sunny: Okay? What's the meaning of the parallelie, guys? Parallelie means, basically, this subgraph 1 and this subgraph 2
Sunny: It says… it should execute.
Sunny: This subgraph 1 and subgraph 2, basically, it should execute in a parallel manner.
Sunny: Got it. So, let me again demonstrate this thing.
Sunny: So, here, guys, what we have, let's say we have… this is my parent graph.
Sunny: Got it. So inside the parent graph, guys, let's say this map, one of the nodes.
Sunny: And let's say this is my subgraph. This is my subgraph, and this is my subgraph.
Sunny: Okay, and then this is what? This is my final graph. Now, earlier, basically, we were running it sequentially. Now, let's say if I wanted to run this particular one parallel.
Sunny: Okay? Parallelly.
Sunny: So, this particular architecture is also called… can you even tell me what it is called, guys?
Sunny: So this particular architecture is… it is also called the fan out.
Sunny: Okay? Now, this particular functionality, this is what this particular functionality is, my graph.
Sunny: Graph 1.
Sunny: And this is what, guys? This is my graph, too.
Sunny: So how I wanted to execute it, guys? I wanted to execute this particular thing parallel.
Sunny: Okay? And this particular thing is also called the fan out. So for that, this langgraph has given us one concept that is called the send method.
Sunny: And in a real time, whenever you are going to design a system, maybe you are going to use this particular method multiple times, okay?
Sunny: So, what is this method, guys? This send method, basically, we use to run the workflow parallelly.
Sunny: To execute the subgraph parallelly.
Sunny: So this is what, guys? This is my subgraph.
Sunny: This is a board guide, this is my subgraph.
Sunny: Okay? So, to execute, to execute, basically, this graph parallelly, right, what we can use, guys, we can use the send, and this is also called the send API. So, how many APIs we understood so far in the, in the lang graph? So, we understood about the state graph.
Sunny: Yes? We understood about the interrupt.
Sunny: Okay? We underst… we… now we are going to be understanding the Sand API.
Sunny: Now, guys, we are going to be understand, in the going forward session, we are going to be understand about the command API also.
Sunny: Okay? This command API, generally, we use it where inside the… multi-agentic system.
Sunny: Getting clear, guys, tell me yes or no, this one.
Sunny: So this particular function, the functionalities are an important one inside the langgraph. Now, tell me, guys, if this diagram is clear, and why to use the send API, if this part is clear, please let me know in the chat.
Sunny: If this part is clear, please let me know.
Sunny: Fanout means what? Fanout means the parallel, paralleling, okay?
Sunny: Fan, how the fan is working. So, let's say this is my fan.
Sunny: There's my friend.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, how I can design the fan? Let's say this is the back side of the fan.
Sunny: And this is the front side of the fan.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, fan is running.
Sunny: So, Keshi, right, how the fan is, like, blowing the air, right?
Sunny: So it's blowing the air like this.
Sunny: This one. So, this is a waterway, this is air, right? So, it is inspired from here itself. Fan.
Sunny: AULK.
Sunny: Fan.
Sunny: Ow.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Fan out.
Sunny: Pan. In.
Sunny: Farin means?
Sunny: The air is coming over here.
Sunny: It's compressing the air, right?
Sunny: Pan out miss.
Sunny: It's blowing the year, like this.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: So, that's a concept, this is called the fan-out. I hope this is clear, tell me how many people are able to understand it.
Sunny: Are you able to understand this particular concept?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now guys, we'll look into the example after the break.
Sunny: So, to use parallel processing, the results should be independent to each other. Yes, it will be independent to each other. I'll show you the code, then you will get a understanding.
Sunny: Can you explain this diagram one more time? Yes, after I explain you the code, again, I will come over here.
Sunny: Okay. So, guys, let's do one thing. Let's, basically take a break, a quick break, and after that, guys, what we will do, we'll look into the example, and again, guys, I will come to this particular explanation. Got it?
Sunny: Yeah, it's going to be a dinner break, right? So, putting a timer for, 20 minutes. After the 20 minute, guys, we'll look into the example. I hope, guys, you are enjoying the session. Are you learning something new? Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Yeah, Lokesh, so sometime. Because already we have… I have explained some of the concepts in the previous class.
Sunny: So, people are not visiting those sessions, or not looking into those solutions.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Great, so let's take a break, and we'll meet after the break. Thank you very much, guys.
Sunny: Okay, guys, can we start with the session? I think everyone is there, just give me a quick thumbs up.
Sunny: So that we can start.
Sunny: Now guys, let's, look into the code. Just a second, guys, I can show you the code.
Sunny: Have you gone through this code? I already shared the code, have you gone through this code?
Sunny: If you have not gone through, please check out this code, guys. Every sort of a code is there inside the IPYNB file.
Sunny: Okay, so now let's understand the uses of the Sand API, how it is working.
Sunny: So, for the send API, the code is going to be start from here.
Sunny: This one, basically.
Sunny: So, first of all, guys, let me load the model and all everything. So, here, guys, this is my model.
Sunny: Okay? I'll be using the model over here. In the earlier example, basically, I have not used the model, so it was just a simple example. So I, shown you some, functionality, right, without using any sort of a model itself.
Sunny: Now guys, here I have initialized the model. Now, just look into the different, different state. So, we have a parent state, which is topic, research, and the final answer. Okay? So, this is the state of my parent node.
Sunny: Then, guys, we have our research worker input, so let me keep the research worker input over here. And this is the, like, this is what, this is the, this is basically a state of the different node, okay? Then we have one other one, so let me,
Sunny: keep it over here in this particular cell. So, the another node is… it's basically a… it would be the research node, right? So, this is the state with respect to that.
Sunny: Okay, now what we are trying to do inside this particular workflow, you will get to know in some time, but just look into this particular state. If you're not getting it, and if you're not getting anything right now, don't worry, you will get in some time.
Sunny: Then, guys, what we are doing, so here, basically, we have a research topic method, okay? So it is taking a state. Now, from the state, it is taking a topic, and then, guys, it is, giving it to the model.
Sunny: And then model, basically, it is going through the topic, and it is returning the response, okay? So this is my first method, which is a research method.
Sunny: So, let me keep it over here in the different cell.
Sunny: Then, guys, we have a summarized topic.
Sunny: Okay, so what it will do, so it will take that particular topic.
Sunny: Okay? And after taking that particular topic, it is going to be summarize that topic. Whatever topic, basically, on whatever topic we are going to perform the research. So, this is a specific prompt related to that. So, let me run it.
Sunny: So, summarize the topic, okay? Then guys, what we have, so, another one, basically, we are going to… we are going to build a graph.
Sunny: So, let's build a graph. So, first, guys, build a subgraph, right? The subgraph… this sub-functionality, right? Sub-working functionality of the parent graph.
Sunny: So, there we have two nodes. The first is a research node, and the second is a, summarize node.
Sunny: Okay? Now, after that, guys, what I will do, so I'll, connect the edges. So, I have a start edge, then it's going to be, to the research topic, then from the research, it is going to the summarized topic. Okay, and then after the summarization, the process will be end. So, this is what, this is my workflow.
Sunny: So I can, run it, now let's run it. And then, guys, I'm going to compile the graph.
Sunny: Right? So this is what… this is a compilation.
Sunny: Now, what I'll do, guys, so I'll show you the graph, how this graph looks like. So, here is my graph, guys, this one.
Sunny: Research sub-agent, okay?
Sunny: I hope this is clear. This graph is clear.
Sunny: So let's keep this graph over the blackboard so that later on I can explain you.
Sunny: I think font size is visible. If I'll do, like, more than this one, then I will not be able to see properly.
Sunny: So, this is what, guys, this is my one of the subgraph, right? Now, what I'm doing, guys, so here I'm going to create one parent graph, okay? So, this is what is my parent graph, guys, so what it is doing is just taking a topic.
Sunny: This particular graph.
Sunny: Sorry, this particular node.
Sunny: So, it is taking a state. From the state, it is taking a topic, and it's just printing a topic, okay? And it's not going to be written anything over here, right? It's not going to be written. So, the method name is what? PrepareTopic.
Sunny: So, let me do one thing, guys, let me run that state. I think we have not executed it so far, but that's why it is giving me the issue. Okay, so this is what is the state of the…
Sunny: This is the state of the parent graph.
Sunny: So guys, let me execute it and see over here.
Sunny: Just look into the method name, you will understand what it is doing. Then, guys, we have another topic, so… sorry, another method. The method name is research worker.
Sunny: Okay, so it is taking a state.
Sunny: And then, from the study, it's taking a topic.
Sunny: Now, guys, what I'm doing, so here is my research subgraph. So this particular subgraph I'm invoking, I'm passing a topic, okay? And then, behalf of that, I'm getting the subgraph result.
Sunny: Okay, and that particular result, I am going to be written from here.
Sunny: So, this is what is my research worker. Got it? So, inside this research worker, I have appended this both graph.
Sunny: Which graph… sorry, I have appended this subgraph. How we are calling? I think you got to know.
Sunny: Now, guys, what I'm doing, so here, research worker input is not defined. Okay, maybe I have not executed the state. Let me execute that. This is done, this is done, this is done. Okay, now everything is done. So, this graph is ready.
Sunny: Now, this is my prepare topic, and this is my research worker. So this is also ready, okay? Then, guys, we have a distributed, distribute topics. So, let me,
Sunny: Basically, execute this one.
Sunny: distribute topic, so it is taking a state. Now, it is passing it through the send API, okay? So, to the send, basically, what we are doing, we are passing… we are passing this particular subgraph.
Sunny: Right? Research worker. Okay, we are passing this particular subgraph. So, this is what is my distributed topic. Okay, now, along with that, we are passing this, topic name also. Then, guys, what we have, we have a final note that is a combined result. So, what it is doing, guys, it is taking the research result.
Sunny: And after taking that, guys, it is going to be… represent the final result. So you can see the… you can see what… you can see the…
Sunny: basically prompt, combine this research summary into one clear explanation. Keep each topic under its own heading, okay? So let me execute it, guys. I hope it is done. Then what I'm doing is, I'm going to build a parent graph. So here is what, here is the state of it.
Sunny: So, let me define the state.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, what we have, so we have a notes over here. So, see, three notes we have. One is a prepare topic, then second is a research worker, and third is a combined result.
Sunny: Okay, so let me define… sorry, let me execute these notes also.
Sunny: Okay? Then, guys, we have our edges. So, start, prepare topic, then we have a conditional edge.
Sunny: prepare topic, it will come to the distributed topic, okay? And then, basically it will, either go to the research work, or basically it will, like, end the process, okay?
Sunny: So, let me, do one thing, let me connect this address. So, here is the execution, just a second, let me run it.
Sunny: So, my graph is ready. So, here, guys, what I can do, I can execute it and show you the graph, how it looks like.
Sunny: So, let me, show you this research graph. See, this is my research graph, guys. Prepare topic, research worker, okay, and then combined result.
Sunny: Okay, so this is what basically is happening. Now, what I'll do, guys, I'll, copy this particular graph, and I'll keep it over the blackboard, so that at the end, I can show you, I can explain this entire one.
Sunny: So, what I have, guys, I have the research worker, which is going to be connected to this subgraph. This is what is my subgraph.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, over here, this research worker is what? This research worker is a subgraph, this one.
Sunny: Okay? Now, how this thing is being running, how this thing is being running, so let me, run it, let me execute it. So, here, guys, you can see, you can see the detail of the graph.
Sunny: So, you can check out the subgraph, and you can check the graph. Both, like, both graphs you can investigate, okay? What is there inside. So, once you will execute this research subgraph, now see over here, we have a start node.
Sunny: then the research topic, then summarize topic, and then end, okay? So, start.
Sunny: Then, research topic, research topic summarize topic, summarize topic to end.
Sunny: This is the complete flow.
Sunny: Now, just investigate this parent graph, what is there. So, let me execute this one over here.
Sunny: Now, see, guys, so we have a start node, okay? Then it will come to the prepare topic.
Sunny: Then it will go to the research worker.
Sunny: Okay, then, combined worker, and then it's going to be end the process.
Sunny: Okay, so how it is working, actually? So, it will start…
Sunny: It will come to the prepare topic. From the prepare topic, it will come to the research worker.
Sunny: from the research worker, it will come to the combined result, combined result to end the process, right? So, it is a parent graph, guys, and inside this one, this subgraph is being integrated, okay? Now, what I'm doing, guys, so here, let me delete this one. I think this 2 graph is clear.
Sunny: Now, after that, guys, what I will do, I will execute it. So, let me test it. So, over here, guys, what I'm doing, so I'm going to be execute this research graph.invoke.
Sunny: researchgraph.invoke, this is my parent graph. Got it? So here we are passing the topic. Let's say my top first topic is a retrieval argument generation, AI agents, and…
Sunny: memory management. So, we are passing 3 topics, okay? So, the research will happen in parallel with respect to all these 3 topics. Got it? So, let me show you how does it work, and here, guys, we'll get the results result inside the list itself. So, let me execute it, and then, guys, I will… if I'll execute it, see.
Sunny: you will get the complete detail. Topic received, retrieval argument generation, AI agent, memory management, worker is starting, so it is doing a research for the retrieval argument generation, subgraph is researching.
Sunny: Okay, worker, AI agent, okay, subgraph is AI agent, okay? Worker is a starting memory management, okay? And then it's doing a research. Then, it is summarizing the result.
Sunny: Okay, of all this one, and then we are getting the final answer. Now, see the final answer of all the… all the topics. So, all the result… all the result, guys, we are get… so all the research basically is happening in the parallel over here.
Sunny: And how it is happening in the parallel, guys, so it is happening, using the send API. So, using the send API, basically, what we can do, we can achieve the parallelism. What we can do, guys, we can achieve the parallelism, we can run the multiple thread over here.
Sunny: Are you getting my point? Is it getting clear to all of you?
Sunny: Yes or no. So, what it will do, guys, it will save your time, okay, for the extensive research. So, common mistake, so this thing will detail, sorry, this thing will discuss in a detail in the next, basically notebook, there I cap the different, different flows, okay? So, first of all, tell me, guys, how many of you are able to understand this entire one?
Sunny: or how many of you want the revision of this entire thing, just let me know in the chat so that I can give you the… I can give you the revision, okay?
Sunny: Do you need a revision?
Sunny: Or, you understood. Now, tell me how much… how much you understood, in percentage. Can you, please let me know the percentage, at least?
Sunny: Great. So, I can see many of you, you are able to understand at least 50-60%, that's the average. Now, 50%, rest 50%, once we'll take a revision, okay, and after that is going to be 100%.
Sunny: Right, so let's do one thing, guys. First, look into the graph.
Sunny: So I hope this graph is clear.
Sunny: Now, this graph is related to what? This graph actually is related to the research.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: This graph, basically, it is related to what? It's related to the research.
Sunny: So, for the research, what we are doing… so over here, we are using the LLM only, means we have created a simple workflow, and whatever topic we are giving to the LLM, and LLM is generating a response, we have found that. Got it? So, how this graph is working, guys, so this is what? This is my parent graph. What is my parent graph, guys?
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: And this is my child graph.
Sunny: Or you can say, this is what is my subgraph.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So, whatever topic we are giving, let's say, guys, what we are doing, we are giving,
Sunny: We are giving 3 topics over here, right, for the… for performing the research. The first topic is going to be…
Sunny: AI agent.
Sunny: The second topic is going to be…
Sunny: drag, okay?
Sunny: And the third topic is going to be… Let's say, fine-tuning.
Sunny: Got it.
Sunny: So I wanted to perform a research.
Sunny: On this 3 topics. How many topics you're getting from the user end?
Sunny: In parallel, you are getting 3 topics. Let's suppose, guys, in parallel, you are getting how many topics?
Sunny: three topics, okay? So, first, it will come to the prepare topic.
Sunny: Now, what this prepare topic is doing, just look into the functionality, you will understand.
Sunny: So, if you will look into the prepare topic.
Sunny: So, where is the prepared topic?
Sunny: Okay, let me search it quickly.
Sunny: So, prepare.
Sunny: topic.
Sunny: Oh, what's her name?
Sunny: Prepare underscore topic.
Sunny: So, prepare underscore…
Sunny: topic.
Sunny: Okay, so we have a prepared topic. Now, see, guys, this is what is my node. Now, what it is doing, guys, it is just taking a topic.
Sunny: Okay? So we're just taking a topic, that's at C.
Sunny: It's from the state, it is just taking a topic, and it is just printing the topic, and it's returning the empty one from here, right? So, it is returning what, guys, it is going to be written the empty dictionary from here, right? Now, guys, what will happen? So, after that, you can see what we have. The next node is going to be…
Sunny: research worker.
Sunny: So what this research worker is doing, so it is taking a topic, guys, from the state itself, okay? So, already, we have our topic inside the state.
Sunny: already we have a topic inside the state, okay? Inside the state. Same state we are sharing throughout the workflow, correct? So, over here, what we will take, we will just take the topic. I mean, this is this method just to, like, showcase the topic, which topic, basically, we are using. Got it?
Sunny: This particular function. Then, guys, we are taking a topic over here, and then we are passing the topic to the subgraph, this one.
Sunny: Is it clear, guys? Tell me yes or no?
Sunny: Is it getting clear to all of you what we are doing over here? So, we are passing this particular topic to where? To the subgraph, okay? So, research, subgraph, invoke, topic, research, and the summary, okay? This particular thing will be getting from the subgraph.
Sunny: Now, let's look into the subgraph, this research subgraph. So, let me show you this particular subgraph.
Sunny: Now, inside this subgraph, what do we have? Inside this research subgraph, okay?
Sunny: So, what is there?
Sunny: Just look into that, see.
Sunny: So, inside the resource subgraph, basically, we have this two functionality.
Sunny: The first is going to be research topic, and the second is going to be a summarized topic, right? So, see, research topic.
Sunny: Okay? So what it is doing, guys, it is taking a topic, and it is doing a research.
Sunny: And then, guys, we have our topic again, and it is doing a summary, right? So, here you can see, we have our, what we are taking, guys, we are taking topic, and we are taking a research, okay, and just, we are going to be summarize it. Got it? Now, how this thing is working in parallel. So, just look over here.
Sunny: So just look over here, guys, how this thing is working parallel.
Sunny: So, we have what? We have a subgraph result. Okay, we have what? We have a research subgraph. We are invoking that, we are invoking with a topic, and then we have a result. Okay, and we are going to return the final result. Now, how this thing is working in a parallel? So, this thing is working parallel over here. So, we are using this distributed topic.
Sunny: And inside this one, we are using this send API, okay? So, to the send API, basically, we are passing this research worker, and this research worker is what? This research worker is my one of the subgraph.
Sunny: This particular subgraph.
Sunny: this particular subgraph, okay? So, what is happening, guys, we have a three topic, AI agents, RAG, and the fine-tuning. Now, this particular topic, basically, it is going in parallel, okay? It is going in parallel to where? To this subgraph.
Sunny: Okay? So, it will take… AI agents?
Sunny: It will take… It will take AI agent, it will take a ragh, It will take fine-tuning.
Sunny: Okay, all this topic…
Sunny: coming where all this topic basically is being passed to this particular graph. Now, how this particular topic is being passed to this, particular subgraph, we are passing it through the SEND API.
Sunny: This one. So, using the Sand API, basically, what we can implement, we can implement the parallelism.
Sunny: Okay? We can implement the fan-out workflow.
Sunny: We can run the multiple thread in parallel.
Sunny: Is it getting clear to all of you? Tell me, yes or no. Is this part getting clear? So again, let me summarize it. So what we are doing, guys, so we have a parent graph.
Sunny: Now, to this parent graph, basically, we have this many nodes. The first is a start node, second is a prepare topic node, third is a research worker node, fourth is a combined result node, and another one is an end node.
Sunny: Now, this prepare topic, what it is doing, guys, it is just taking a topic, okay? Just printing the topic. That is passing the result to the research worker, this one.
Sunny: Now, the research worker, basically.
Sunny: Okay, this research worker, we are calling in parallel. How we are calling this research worker in parallel? Using the SEND API.
Sunny: Okay, so using the SEND API, basically, we are calling this research worker in parallel. So let's say we have a three topic, AI agent, RAG, and the fine-tuning. So for all the three topics, the first topic.
Sunny: The second topic and the third topic. It is calling this particular subgraph in parallel.
Sunny: How many of you are able to understand?
Sunny: First of all, tell me, is this architecture clear? If this architecture is clear, please let me know.
Sunny: Yes?
Sunny: Okay. Now, again, let's look into the code, so that you will get the clear-cut understanding that what is happening over there.
Sunny: So, guys, here we have what we have a research worker.
Sunny: Okay, this one. So, research worker basically is doing a research for… we are calling this particular subgraph. Now, we have a distributed topic, okay? Now, here we'll get a state.
Sunny: Now, we are basically passing through the send, okay? This is my send method. Now, what we are passing, guys, we are passing the research worker, this one, and the topic name.
Sunny: Okay, so we are iterating over the topic, and we are passing it over here to the send. Got it? And then we are going to combine the result. So, guys, let's look into the connectivity. So, after looking into the connectivity only, you will understand how this entire thing is happening.
Sunny: Okay? So, over here, guys, you can see, so we have a state, okay, state graph. Now, here we are passing the parent state. Now, just look into the parent state, what we have defined inside the parent state. So, we have a topic, we have our result, okay, and then we have a final answer. So, this is what we have inside the parent state, this one.
Sunny: Then we have one more state, guys. This is why research worker input. So, topic is my research worker input. So, someone was asking, sir, can we define the different different state? Yes, so you can define the different different state in this way, but guys, please, like, use the same key, okay? If, something is there inside a parent state, okay, use the same key inside a child state also.
Sunny: Otherwise, it might break.
Sunny: So, we have topic over here. So, in the research, basically, we just require the topic. So, we have defined the topic. One more, one more state with the topic. In the research, basically, what we required, we required a topic, okay, we required the research and summary. So, see, guys, this topic actually is coming from here? This topic actually is coming from here.
Sunny: Okay? So, keep the key name as the same, whatever you wanted to inherit from the parent. Otherwise, you will get an error. Okay, let's say you wanted to use this topic, this one, topic, okay? Then keep that, that particular name over here. Now guys, what I'm doing, so just a second, let me again show you. So, research topic is doing nothing, it's just doing a research, actually.
Sunny: Okay? Summarized topic is just summarizing the detail.
Sunny: This is my, subgraph.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Then, guys, you can see, we are going to be compile that subgraph, and this is my subgraph, guys, this one.
Sunny: Now, guys, here is my prepared topic. It is just showing the detail of the topic. Then we have a research worker, so it will, basically call the subgraph.
Sunny: Then, guys, we have a distributed topic, so here we are going to be called the send method. So it is sending the request to each and every, it is sending a request to subgraph with respect to each and every topic in parallel.
Sunny: So, 3 parallel thread is running for me here.
Sunny: Then we are going to be combine the result, okay? So this is all the overall functionality. Now, guys, we are going to be building a graph, parent graph, so this is my state. Now, here, guys, we are going to be at the edge.
Sunny: So, this is my first stage, guys. Now, you can see the first stage is what? Prepare topic. Sorry, first node is a prepared topic. The second node is a research worker, and the third one is a combined result.
Sunny: Now, just look into the connectivity, okay? So, we have a start, we are passing the detail to prepare topic. Now, from the prepare topic, guys, it is going to the distributed topic.
Sunny: Okay? It is going here, guys, it is going to the distributed topic. Now, just look into this in this way. So, first is, it is going to the prepared topic. Now, prepare topic is going to the distributed topic, and now look into the distributed topic, what's going to be returned. So, distributed topic, basically, it's going to be returned the result, actually.
Sunny: Okay? So, we are having a state. From that, we are getting a topic. We are topic, passing a topic name over here, along with our subgraph node, and it is running in parallel, right? And then, guys, what we have, we have a distributed topic over here. This one.
Sunny: This one. Start with
Sunny: Prepare topic, distribute this one. Basically, prepare topic, it's going to the distributed topic, okay? And from here, guys, what we are getting, we are getting the detail, the final answer, okay?
Sunny: Now guys, after that, what is happening? So, research worker, actually, this one, it's going to be connect where, it's going to be connect to the combined result. Combined result, basically, is going to be connected to the end.
Sunny: That's it, guys. Nothing else.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: I hope this entire thing is getting clear now, what is there inside the distributed topic, and what's going to be returned, okay? So, after that, guys, see, we are going to be executed.
Sunny: So, if you will see the execution, so what we are getting, guys, we are getting the detail. So, everything is running in parallel. You can try out with any sort of other topic.
Sunny: let's say I'm running it with a different topic, so it will perform the research with respect to each and every topic, okay? So, here…
Sunny: instead of the retrieval argument generation, let's say I'm writing.
Sunny: American.
Sunny: dollar.
Sunny: Now, here I am passing the, let's say, Indian rupee.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: India.
Sunny: Rupees.
Sunny: Now here, what I'm passing, guys, let's say I'm passing.
Sunny: What I can pass. Let's say, Koveti…
Sunny: Kuwet currency, okay? Koveti Dhina, right? So, we're doing, research on top of it, on top of this particular topic, right? American dollar, Indian rupees, and the Koveti Dhina, okay? So, let me take this particular topic, and let me call the research over here.
Sunny: Now see, guys, if I learn it, now see. American topic received, American dollar, okay, so worker is started, American dollar, research is started. Indian dollar, research is started. Kavitha, research is started. Now see how fast we got the answer.
Sunny: Even though we are doing a research on top of three topics, means we are generating a result for the three topics, but it is very fast, very quick. And in parallel, guys, it is happening, with respect to each and every topic. Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: How many people are able to understand it now?
Sunny: Yeah, we can do the research for the Oracle share also.
Sunny: So, actually, it is not taking your data in the real time right now.
Sunny: Okay, so if we are going to be connect that functionality, it will take the data in real time. So, did you understand, did you understand, basically.
Sunny: Did you understand, guys, yes or no?
Sunny: Did you understand how the SEND API is working?
Sunny: I just wanted to know that particular part.
Sunny: Yes or no?
Sunny: Yes, how Sand API is working in parallel? So, you just need to be provide that… you just need to be provide.
Sunny: basically…
Sunny: You just need to provide input like this, okay? If it's not getting clear, so what you can do, you can keep it in a single line, just to understand what we are passing. So we are passing the research worker, means we are passing the node.
Sunny: Okay, the subgraph node, and we are iterating on each and every topic. So it is running everything in a parallel over here. That's it, guys.
Sunny: As simple as that. Okay.
Sunny: Great. So, guys, I hope this is clear. Now, tell me, okay, one more thing I would like to ask you. Did you understand the meaning of this particular concept over here?
Sunny: This one. This one.
Sunny: Did you understand the concept of this particular, did you understand the concept over here? I think some of you are having a confusion with respect to this particular topic, right? Sorry, with respect to this particular…
Sunny: With respect to this particular edge, right? So, I can explain you the working of this edge, I can explain you how this thing is working. Okay, so just give me a moment, I can explain you over the Blackboard itself. So, let's say, guys, what is happening. I can explain you over here.
Sunny: I'm taking what, I'm taking this particular code.
Sunny: I am taking this particular code.
Sunny: And I'm keeping it over here, over the blackboard.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So this is what is my code.
Sunny: No, guys, just tell me, what is happening?
Sunny: What is happening, guys?
Sunny: So, first, it's going to be start from this prepare topic.
Sunny: first is going to be start from this prepare topic, okay? So this is my prepare topic, this one.
Sunny: What is this? It's a prepare topic. Now, after the prepare topic, what is happening, guys? Tell me, it's going to the distributed topic. Now, inside the distributed topic only, the Sand API is being called
Sunny: Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: in this distributed topic only, the send API is being called.
Sunny: Now, what this Sand API is returning?
Sunny: So, the SEND API, actually, the SEND API, it is returning an output, right? So, over here, we'll get an output in the form of…
Sunny: List.
Sunny: If we will look over here, if we will look into the code.
Sunny: If you will look in the code, you will get it.
Sunny: See? So, it is going to be written a result, so we're getting a result over here.
Sunny: Now, where this result is going?
Sunny: Okay, so again, where we are passing this particular result, so we are passing this result to the research worker, this one.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: Okay. Now, over here, see, what we are doing, what we are doing, see, here, the conditional edge, what is the meaning of the conditional edge? So, after the orchestration, what we are doing, we are running this function.
Sunny: Okay, we are run… after… see, inside the orchestration, we are running this function, this distributed topic, okay? And it's going to be written the value.
Sunny: Right? And after returning a value, so it's going to be decided where the execution will go.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: where the execution will go. So, how I can explain you guys, let's say, send API is sending a request.
Sunny: First topic is our rack, second is our agent, third is our fine-tuning. Okay? So, how many worker we have over here? We have a 3 worker over here. Got it? So, after that, guys, see, we have an orchestrator.
Sunny: Okay, we have passed the… what we have done, guys, we have passed the detail, right, to the graph. And after running all this thing, after running the Sand API and all, we are getting a result. Now, here we are telling… go to this research worker again, this one, research worker again, after getting a result. Now, just look over here.
Sunny: Just look over here. What we have inside the research worker.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: what we have inside the research worker. So in the research worker, basically, we are taking a topic.
Sunny: Okay? Then, we have what? ResearchSubgraph.invoke, right? Research subgraph.invoke, so here, basically.
Sunny: We are calling the topic and all, and we are getting the result. Now, what… from… see, we are getting the result, okay? And, the result basically is coming where this result is coming from here. There's a research result, okay? Inside this particular key, this, this is being mentioned, okay?
Sunny: So, what is happening, guys? So, this to function is automatically deciding.
Sunny: That's why we have put it inside the… that's why, guys, we have put it inside… we have… we have put it inside the conditional edge.
Sunny: Okay, it's going to be decided where needs to be go. Do we still continue the research, or do I need to stop the process?
Sunny: means I need to further pass the detail to the combined result. So this is what it is doing.
Sunny: Making sense or not?
Sunny: So, it is for the dynamic execution.
Sunny: It's for the dynamic execution. This true function is deciding, basically, where to go. Do I still need to be processed the research, or I need to be stopped it?
Sunny: Got it, guys, yes or no?
Sunny: Okay, I will explain with another example. In that case, it will be clear.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Actually, see, you can pass this… this one, no? You can pass this particular value without the list also, that is also fine, this one.
Sunny: Research worker. This one.
Sunny: Okay. You can pass this particular thing without the list also. Okay, so let's see if I'm going to pass it like this. In that case, also, it will be working. See, let me show you.
Sunny: This is fine, this is fine.
Sunny: And this is fine, see? Research result. Now, if I'm going to be run it…
Sunny: See, I'll still be… I'll be getting a result.
Sunny: Okay, so see, we are getting a result. Now, if I'm going to be called it for this one…
Sunny: So we're getting a result, okay? So the list is not mandatory over there. The list, symbol is not mandatory. Without that, also, you can pass.
Sunny: Guys, I can show you with one simple diagram, just a second. I had that simple diagram, just a second. I'm pasting it over the blackboard, okay? So, what is happening, guys? See?
Sunny: how many workers we have? Let's say we are passing 3 topics.
Sunny: Okay, we have an orchestrator, this one.
Sunny: We have what? We have orchestrator, okay?
Sunny: Means our graph. It is assigning a worker. Now, for every topic, guys, let's say it is assigning 3 worker, rack, agents, and memory. How many worker we have? Worker 1, worker 2, and worker 3. Till here, everything is fine, yes or no.
Sunny: Yes? Now, how we are going to be assigned this worker? So, let's say this is a function for assigning the worker, this one.
Sunny: This is our distributed function. This is our distributed function, tell me yes or no. I can rename this particular function as a distributed one.
Sunny: So, where is my distributed function?
Sunny: This is mine.
Sunny: distributed topic. Okay, this one. So, what I can do, guys, now I can…
Sunny: Rename it, okay?
Sunny: The name of it, it's going to be a distributed topics.
Sunny: Let's rename over here also.
Sunny: This is what, guys, distributed topic. Now, tell me, is it clear? So, we have this function, and what it is doing, it is pass, it is going to be create a 3 worker.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, how this thing is being decided over here.
Sunny: Okay, so this thing is being decided using what? Using the SEND API.
Sunny: Okay. Using what, guys? Using the Send API.
Sunny: Okay, and this conditional edge basically is helping it… helping us over here. So, let's say I'm putting the… putting one more function over here. Just see… focus over here, guys, see? This one.
Sunny: This is my one more example. So, let's say builder.addConditional Edge. Now, over here, what I'm doing, I'm passing this particular name, this one.
Sunny: distributed topic.
Sunny: So, we have, we have, we have our orchestrator.
Sunny: Okay? And now, see, add conditional edge.
Sunny: Add conditional edge, orchestrated distributed topic. Okay, so actually, our entire flow is running between these two functions, and automatically, dynamically, it is deciding.
Sunny: Dynamically, it is deciding, actually.
Sunny: Now, understood.
Sunny: Okay. So, it is not mandatory that always RAG will be sent over here. Let's say first agent is being sent over here. Then, second time, RAG will be sent.
Sunny: Okay? RAG will be sent the third time, let's say first time, agent is being sent, memory is being sent, so then ragh will be sent, okay? So the order is not defined.
Sunny: Function automatically is being decided using this conditional Aj, okay?
Sunny: For which all topic, we need to be execute this entire flow.
Sunny: Now, is it clear?
Sunny: I hope, guys, that is clear. I'll show you more examples, so that, in that case, it will be clarified.
Sunny: maybe some more confusion might be left, so I'll do that, right? So, guys, can we take 2 minutes of break? Then again, I will explain to you the different, different workflow, and then tomorrow we'll understand about the multi-agentic system. Tell me, can we, basically take,
Sunny: Tomato break, and then, I'll explain the different workflow. Again, this part will come in the next workflow, okay? I kept it over there.
Sunny: Again, this part will come.
Sunny: Yes, you can send this way, Abhijit.
Sunny: Right? You can say in this particular way.
Sunny: So, fine, guys, putting 2 minutes of timer, just a quick water break, and after that, guys, we'll start.
Sunny: The next notebook, there, basically, we have a different, different workflow. So, putting 2 minutes of timer, a quick water break.
Sunny: Okay, guys, let's, start. I think, everyone is there, right?
Sunny: Just give me a quick confirmation, guys.
Sunny: Okay, back. Okay, give me a moment, guys, I'm going to start the session.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So guys, what we are going to do… now, we are going to be understand, the different, different workflow, okay?
Sunny: So, I'm going to be open the… another notebook, and inside that particular notebook, I kept the different, different orchest data. So, in today's class, guys, I'll just give you the quick walkthrough of that.
Sunny: And the next class we'll discuss, and along with that, we'll discuss the multi-agentic flow also, that how we can design the multi-agentic flow inside the langgraph. Got it, guys? Yes or no? Is it getting clear?
Sunny: Great.
Sunny: So, now, see, this is all the details, which I capped. You can definitely read out all this detail, just for your understanding. So, whenever you are going to revise the concept, you can directly revise the concept from here itself.
Sunny: So, if we are talking about a different, different workflow, right, different, different orchestrator, so the first, one, we have a sequential workflow. The second one, we have parallelization workflow.
Sunny: Fan in and fan out. Then we have a conditional routing.
Sunny: Then we have orchestrator and worker with the Sand API, Evaluator Optimizer loop, and Tool Calling Agent. Now, can anyone tell me, guys, how many of… how many, workflow we have already completed, how many workflows we have already learned?
Sunny: So we just kind of revision.
Sunny: How many workflows we have completed so far.
Sunny: No, I'm saying in the entire,
Sunny: In the entire one, basically.
Sunny: Okay, so we completed what, guys? We completed this one, the conditional routing we have completed. We have completed this orchestration worker with send, okay? And then, guys, we have completed this one also, the tool calling agent loop.
Sunny: Did you, you know, right? So, in the previous classes, we had under… we basically discussed about this tool calling JetLoop also, this one.
Sunny: Yes or no? So, in the previous classes, guys, we understood about this tool calling agent loop also, okay?
Sunny: Conditional routing, we already understood.
Sunny: We understood about this orchestration worker with the send one. Parallelization, how manually, basically, we can parallelize… means,
Sunny: We can send the request in a panel work node, so that also we understood, right? Sequential workflow means we are sending the re… we are sending the data in a sequence itself. So, whenever we are talking about the langgraph guys, so these are the workflow, okay? These are the different orchestrators we have.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: Okay. A tool calling agent loop means what? So, we have a LLM. So, let's say this is my LLM, and LLM dynamically taking decision.
Sunny: L&M dynamically taking decision, which Tool needs to be called.
Sunny: LLM dynamically taking decision which tool needs to be called.
Sunny: So, that comes under the tool calling Agentic Loop. Specifically, I have discussed that particular part. Now let's, look into the other one. So, let's start from the sequential workflow itself. It is just kind of revision, guys. Again, I'm saying, so this notebook, basically, it's going to be a revision, okay?
Sunny: So, here in the sequence, sequential workflow.
Sunny: What, we are doing, guys, so we are following the fixed sequence.
Sunny: In the parallelization, parallel, fan out, and fan in.
Sunny: In routing, guys, one dynamically selected branch, okay? The conditional routing. Orchestrator worker, dynamic fan out with send. So this is what, basically, we were learning.
Sunny: As of now, in the previous solution. Evaluator optimizer means feedback loop with 3 attempt limit, or basically any number of limit we can keep.
Sunny: Agent loop means what? Model control tool loop. Okay? So here, model, control, the tool loop. So this is what, guys, this is like, this is a different, different control flow.
Sunny: Okay, inside we're inside the langram. Again, I'm saying, guys, this notebook is a kind of revision, whatever we have learned so far.
Sunny: No guys, see, let me explain over the Blackboard itself. So, I can open the Blackboard. Give me a moment.
Sunny: Yeah. So it is visible, guys. My blackboard is visible.
Sunny: Now, here, guys, the first one is going to be a sequential workflow.
Sunny: Sequential.
Sunny: workflow.
Sunny: Now, in the sequential workflow, what we have.
Sunny: So the sequential workflow, basically, we have a node, right? Let's say, this is my first node.
Sunny: This is my second node.
Sunny: This is my third node, this is my fourth node.
Sunny: So everything… everything is running, everything is being executed in the sequence.
Sunny: Got it, guys? Yes or no?
Sunny: So, this is called the sequential workflow. Now, what is a parallel workflow, guys? So, the second is called the parallel workflow.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Paralyzation.
Sunny: Or parallel workflow.
Sunny: Now, let's say… We have multiple nodes.
Sunny: This is my one of the nodes, this is my one of the nodes, right? This is my one of the nodes, this is my one of the nodes.
Sunny: Now, this entire node basically is passing the input to any one node, this one.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: So, it is kind of parallelization. Tell me yes or no.
Sunny: Now, this particular thing is called what? This particular thing is called the fan in.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Now, the second one basically fan out.
Sunny: It could be a vice versa also.
Sunny: Vice versa means what?
Sunny: So let's say, we have one node, this one.
Sunny: Okay, and it is passing the output to the multiple node. This one.
Sunny: So this is also a parallel.
Sunny: parallel flow.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, here, guys, what we have, we have.
Sunny: this one. Let's say node, and from here, it is passing the data to the other node. So this is called FENOUT.
Sunny: So, in parallelization, we implement this fan out, fan in and fan out, okay? This one.
Sunny: Then guys, another one is called the routing.
Sunny: I think you already know about the routing.
Sunny: conditional routing.
Sunny: If I'm saying routing, so the meaning of it, it's a conditional routing.
Sunny: Okay. Then the conditional routing… We have a dynamic branch.
Sunny: So, let's say this is my node. We have two nodes, this one.
Sunny: And this one.
Sunny: So, based on some logic only, we are going to be decide.
Sunny: Whether this thing needs to be executed, or this thing needs to be executed.
Sunny: So this is called the conditional branch.
Sunny: Understood, guys? Yes or no? It's also called the conditional edge.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Now, guys, we have one more that is called the Orchestator Worker.
Sunny: The fourth is called the orchestrator worker.
Sunny: Okay? Now, we have two things over here, the orchestrator.
Sunny: And the second is the worker.
Sunny: Now, this worker, basically, it is related to this fan-out approach.
Sunny: Generally, we are using what? We are using the send API over here.
Sunny: Now, dynamically, it is deciding. Dynamically, it is deciding. So, let's say we have node, right?
Sunny: And, we have Node, right? This is what is my orchestator.
Sunny: The input is coming.
Sunny: Now, here we have… we have what? We have implemented the walker.
Sunny: Now, this worker, actually, it is sending the request to 3 nodes.
Sunny: Okay? Three different. So, it is sending… sorry, it is sending a request to the node, okay? In parallel, actually, it is sending.
Sunny: It is running 3 different threads. It can run multiple threads, okay? 3 threads.
Sunny: this worker.
Sunny: So this could be the subgraph, this could be any specific node, this one. They are actually sending the request. It would be one node only, let's say it could be the subgraph.
Sunny: A proper subgraph.
Sunny: Or it could be a single node also.
Sunny: Okay? So to this particular subgraph or to this particular node, it is passing the request in parallel.
Sunny: This one. This worker.
Sunny: And here, guys, this… using this… we are using send now, so this particular request is going to be a conditional one.
Sunny: Conditional means what? This worker, actually, it's going to be connected to this orchestrator, In the conditional manner.
Sunny: Tell me, yes or no, it is getting clear or not, this one.
Sunny: So, dynamically it is picking the topic, dynamically it is picking a topic, and it's trying to execute this one, this worker.
Sunny: This is what, basically, we were seeing inside the last subgraph.
Sunny: This is what, basically, we were saying inside the last subgraph. This is what, basically, we were saying inside the last subgraph, practical, okay? So, conditionally, guys, this is connecting, this one.
Sunny: This one, this burger, actually, with this. Now, how it is connecting? It's connecting via the send.
Sunny: SAN API.
Sunny: sorry, using the send API, basically sending a request, using the conditional edge only, it's going to be connected, okay? This particular request is being passed via SEND API, this one, the parallel request.
Sunny: Okay, use the conditional edge, conditional edge.
Sunny: It's going to be connected to the orchestrator.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Is it getting clear? This one? The fifth one, the fifth one is called the Agentic loop. This…
Sunny: Tool calling loop, okay?
Sunny: Why we are seeing the Agentic loop? Because model itself taking a decision over here, dynamically.
Sunny: which tool needs to be called? Tool 1, Tool 2, Tool 3, Tool 4. So we are binding the tool to the model, tool1, tool2,
Sunny: 2, 3… tool for… You're binding the tool to the model.
Sunny: And model itself is taking a decision which tool needs to be called.
Sunny: We are not binding the tool to the workflow. That's another thing, different thing. Already discussed in the previous classes.
Sunny: Okay? We are binding a tool…
Sunny: To the model directly, and model dynamically taking a decision.
Sunny: which tool needs to be called, so this is called the NAR.
Sunny: model.
Sunny: Control.
Sunny: tool.
Sunny: Loop.
Sunny: model control tool loop, okay? And the other one is called the Evaluator and the optimizer.
Sunny: This one.
Sunny: Sixth one is called the… Evaluator.
Sunny: Evaluator.
Sunny: Optimizer.
Sunny: So, inside the evaluator and optimizer, what we have, guys, so we have a feedback loop, actually.
Sunny: Right? We have a feedback loop. Now, how does it work, guys?
Sunny: So… Let's say… this is mine.
Sunny: a start point.
Sunny: Then it will go to the next node, generator node.
Sunny: Then, it will go to the evaluator node.
Sunny: Okay? Now, this evaluator node basically is going to be decided. The solution need to be accepted.
Sunny: Or… again… We need to pass this thing.
Sunny: to the… generator.
Sunny: So, this evaluator… It's going to be decided.
Sunny: what needs to be done, right? So, it will pass this particular input again to the generator.
Sunny: It will add some improvement, okay? The improvement is required.
Sunny: Plus… It will provide some feedback.
Sunny: And… my generator… Again…
Sunny: will generate that… generate that particular output. So, this is called the evaluator Optimizer one. It's here, basically, we just have the feedback loop, that's it.
Sunny: So, this is the main workflow, basically, which I've been, basically, which I've been defined inside the langgraph, which have been defined here inside the langgraph, documentation. Got it, guys?
Sunny: So, now guys, tell me, how many of you are still confused inside this one? Orchestrator and worker? Should I take another example of it? This one? Orchestrator and worker?
Sunny: Yeah, so I'm thinking to take it in the next class. I think, you all are career. So after taking this example, one by one, I'll take an example. All the example is there already, inside the notebook.
Sunny: Okay, so we'll understand it, we'll take a… we'll take a look onto it. I think within half an hour, one hour, we can complete, and then we'll move to the multi-agentic flow.
Sunny: Understood?
Sunny: Is it getting clear?
Sunny: We'll move to the multi-agentic flow.
Sunny: Yeah, one example will be enough. So, guys, this notebook, actually, it's a kind of revision of your langgraph. So, for whatever we have learned, it's going to be a revision of all those things.
Sunny: Now, what… where we will go, guys, we'll go to the multi-entic flow.
Sunny: And after this one, guys, we'll…
Sunny: move, right? So after class number 48, let me write a topic over here. For a topic, we are going to be complete. So after that, guys, we'll move to the…
Sunny: MCP.
Sunny: Okay? So we'll learn about the MCP.
Sunny: Class number, where it went, guys, this one. Class number 49.
Sunny: Gloss.
Sunny: MCP.
Sunny: 26, 27.
Sunny: So, it's going to be 2627.
Sunny: Rename, guys. 26?
Sunny: 2026, okay. We'll learn about the MCP, guys.
Sunny: So we'll understand what is a MCP, and we'll run the multiple example. After that, guys, in the class 49, we'll probably learn about the
Sunny: Guard rails, okay?
Sunny: So, class number 50. What is this? Class number 50, right? So, 26, 27 of September.
Sunny: Okay, so here, guys, we'll learn about the…
Sunny: Guard rails, how we can put the guardrails and all.
Sunny: And then, guys, after that, we'll learn about the… Evaluation, okay?
Sunny: So, class 51 basically is going to further evaluation. So I'm writing just to remind, what is going to be the next topic. This class might be… might be extend also.
Sunny: So, here, guys, then we have, first off.
Sunny: Okay, 3rd of October, when is the next Saturday, Sunday? Okay, 3rd of October, right? So, this is going to be 3rd of October.
Sunny: So we'll learn the evaluation with the one specific package, one… with one specific, like, this, framework that's called the Deep Eval, okay? Whichever framework we are using in our industry, okay, I'll just, told you the name, okay? And we can use those specific framework for implementing it. Got it?
Sunny: Great. In the MCP itself, I can include the A2 and all. So, MCPN, it will… let me rename it.
Sunny: A to A.
Sunny: Okay, so these are the upcoming topic, guys. After this one, we'll start the project. So whatever Agentic rag, this, that, whatever projects are there on the end-to-end project, so we'll do it after this one only, because then only it will make sense.
Sunny: Nitin and the cloud code, these two topics will be there with respect to the no-code AI, so that I will cover after completing the entire syllabus.
Sunny: Okay, let me show you the syllabus.
Sunny: So, I think this is the syllabus, this one.
Sunny: Okay, evaluation strategy.
Sunny: Guardrails.
Sunny: Then MCP, right? This three main topics around the agent, okay, and the system. Then cloud services for the Gen AI in project, we will cover up, this one.
Sunny: no code agent tool, right? So, inside this one, no code agent tool, Nitin, and that's Cloud Automation Mastery. So, this will do after completing the end-to-end project, because this is not related… this topic is not related to our development site.
Sunny: Okay? We'll do the end-to-end project, this one, this project, this project, and this 3 project.
Sunny: So here itself, we'll discuss about all the deployment, all the cloud, everything, guys. So from there, this project itself, I'll teach you every sort of a cloud and all. Cloud code, and this Nitin, actually, it is off-topic, okay? So it is not… it does not come inside this development flow.
Sunny: Making sense or not?
Sunny: So that I will take after completing the syllabus, okay?
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, guys, I think, we are good to go today, so…
Sunny: Yeah, Will will teach you the deployment, Will will discuss that Anura.
Sunny: Okay, I think we are good to go with today's session. Now, let's, conclude it.
Sunny: Was there a committee support for the interpretation? Yes, committee is already there, you can ask, for any sort of help, definitely will help us.
Sunny: Cloud code is nothing, it's very simple to implement. We just have to be configured the cloud, and then we have to understand how the cloud code works, Cloud SQL works, and Cloud Core Work work, that's it. Nothing is there. Okay?
Sunny: So, you cannot become a champion just by seeing my session. You will become a, used to of that tool once you will start using it.
Sunny: Let's say, if I tell you, let's take a tutorial on WhatsApp, let's take a tutorial for the Instagram.
Sunny: I can explain to you how WhatsApp works, I can explain you how Instagram works, right? But until you're not using that specific application, you will not understand what is happening inside.
Sunny: So…
Sunny: I can… I will teach you Claude code, cloud autonomy and all, with the skill, with the co-work and all, but…
Sunny: Until you're not going to do it, you will not be habitual of that tool.
Sunny: It is just an AI tool for our use. We are not building that tool at all.
Sunny: It is giving a flexibility to us for putting some detail over there, the data, it can generate the script on a dynamic manner. That is a, like, very useful feature of the clot, and that's why it is being used in enterprises.
Sunny: I've used a skill, it is a very useful feature. Even you can use that. You can use the cloud code, it is, again, a useful co-pilot, but it takes money, okay? So we'll do that, we'll understand.
Sunny: After this, can we make our own cloud code?
Sunny: No, Ava.
Sunny: Your cloud code, how you will make your own cloud code.
Sunny: Yeah, you can build a simple, means the basic, basic Agentic flow for the coding agent kind of stuff, you can do that. For the full-fledged cloud course, like, a very heavy, thing, right? So for that, like, that… lots of engineering will be required in the back end.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Yep.
Sunny: Okay, guys, so I hope you like the flow. Tell me, did you like the flow of the sessions? I think everything we are covering in a sequence only. Now, we'll cover remaining thing in terms of the project, guys. Don't worry, I'll not leave anything. Whatever, basically I told you, I teach everything.
Sunny: So, just go through with this entire material, it's quite useful. Generate your own notes out of this material, provide to the cloud, Chad GPT, and ask to evaluate this material, ask the ranking, just do some
Sunny: ask the, like, the number how effective this material is, if it can add, add on, if anything can be added on on top of it. Just add on and learn from there itself, prepare for the interview.
Sunny: I make sure, guys, you can crack, any GenAI interview after learning these many things, because no one will ask you out of this one, okay? So, if you're good to go, then I think…
Sunny: If you're good to learn all this thing, then you can correct the interview.
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: So, please respond to this question, which question? Or should I have taken any another topic, or do the project tag interview?
Sunny: Yeah, I would suggest, if you are experienced in any domain, that do the project in that domain, okay, and then showcase in the interview. You can take my project as a reference project, and you can implement any project. Got it? You should always work in that manner. You should take a reference of any project, okay, and then, work on your ideas.
Sunny: Making sense?
Sunny: Okay, fine guys, I think we can close the session. Thank you guys, thank you very much for joining the session.
Sunny: I'll see you in the next class. Thank you very much. Okay?
Sunny: Yeah, thank you. Putting a 2-minute timer so that if no one is having doubt, you can drop that session.
Sunny: And after that, we'll start the doubt session, okay?
Sunny: Okay, guys, let's start with the doubt session. So, if you have any doubt, you can raise your hand.
Sunny: I'll take your doubts, okay?
Sunny: Yeah, Vikas, what's the doubt?
Vikas Verma: Hi, Sunny.
Sunny: Hello.
Vikas Verma: Asuni, so, my discussion is regarding the multimodal rag.
Vikas Verma: Which we had a class, and my question is that I was creating that project, which you gave as an assignment to us, so do we need to submit that assignment after completion for your review, or just… this is just for our practice?
Sunny: Yeah, you can, basically do it right now as a practice. If you want to submit, you can submit it via, Google Form, okay? I hope you have that Google Form, correct?
Vikas Verma: Could you please share the clothing? I mean, it's lost somewhere.
Sunny: Okay, okay, I'll share that.
Vikas Verma: Thank you so much. And, second thing is that, while, doing, you know, taking the class, you use 3 PDFs at that point in time. So, while doing
Vikas Verma: this assignment. Do we need to take another PDF, or we can utilize the other two PDFs which,
Vikas Verma: you shared, I mean, used while, taking the class.
Sunny: Which 3PDFs, sorry?
Vikas Verma: You used 3DFs while taking the class of multi-model rag, and then you created that system, and we showed that how embedding is getting done, and how the model is working.
Sunny: It wasn't.
Vikas Verma: bit confused which PDF I should use. I, I, did some, LLM search.
Vikas Verma: So, the PDF should be that. It has images, the graphs, and the tables, all those contents, so that the.
Sunny: Correct, correct, correct. You can take that one.
Vikas Verma: Yeah, so… the one which you shared, because the PDF that you used were…
Vikas Verma: only one, which you showed the practical on. There are two more PDFs.
Vikas Verma: So, should we use that, or we should use some other PDF, or you can suggest a better one so that we can practice more on that?
Sunny: No, you can use that one only, which I shared right now. On top of it, you can build. Otherwise, there are so many data over the internet itself, you can bring some data from there as well, some typical PDF and all, okay?
Vikas Verma: Okay.
Vikas Verma: And, one more thing. I was doing… while doing that project, I also tested the, ChadGPT. I… I sent the entire rubric that you shared for that project, and I'm being very honest, so I asked the LM to create the content, and he created the entire
Vikas Verma: Code and everything.
Vikas Verma: And I kept that just for the reference. So, should we use that practice or not?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, yeah, this practice is very common nowadays, so you should do that practice only.
Vikas Verma: Okay, so I was a little confused whether should I do it or not. Let's ask you, because if that is the right way to learn these things nowadays or not.
Sunny: No, no, no, this is a common practice, you should go in this way only.
Vikas Verma: Dude.
Vikas Verma: Okay, and one last thing, when we will be starting… when we will be going into the project phase next month, so how much time we are securing for completion of the project, but that… because that would be the most important time for all of us to understand end-to-end of
Vikas Verma: The entire, you know, journey that we have, taken so far.
Vikas Verma: Is it one month time period that you secured for that, or more than that?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, we'll take one month, okay? Until we are not completing all the things, we'll take… we'll do that, okay? So, you can assume at least one month.
Vikas Verma: Okay, thank you so much, Sunny. Thank you so much.
Sunny: Yeah.
Vikas Verma: Right.
Sunny: Okay, Vikas is done now. Bhagwandas, what's your doubt?
bhagwandas armani: Yeah, hi. So, a couple of doubts, okay. So, you have shown the langgraph with the various, what you can say.
bhagwandas armani: various ways to configure or, write the langgraphs, right? So, typically, how many edges that you see in your langgraph and, in your practical life, and also.
bhagwandas armani: Can there be something called a persistent graph? Let us say you have 10 steps, okay, in the graph, okay? Let us say 3 steps are done, and there is something happened, outage happened, or AG resiliency happened.
bhagwandas armani: How can we move that step… move the remaining 7 steps onto the other AIC, or something like that? Is that a possibility?
bhagwandas armani: That is question number one. Second is, the question is, I mean, let us say we give a prompt, and finally, it will have to, in order to initiate a langgraph, it have… we have to create a state… state instance.
bhagwandas armani: So, how do we convert the, what you can say, the prompt into the suite?
bhagwandas armani: Okay.
bhagwandas armani: That's the second question I have.
Sunny: Prompt into the state.
bhagwandas armani: Yeah.
bhagwandas armani: See, langgraph requests a state object, right?
bhagwandas armani: Okay, now, but in general, if you are using, if you are adopting implication into practical, we will generally, we'll get, you say, something called a, prompt.
bhagwandas armani: Okay.
bhagwandas armani: And from the prompt, we have to go ahead and initiate a, what you can say, langgraph.
bhagwandas armani: Okay, now, in order to create a langgraph, the prompt have to be converted into a state object.
Sunny: Okay, okay, so I explained to you that it's structure output one, no? Just use that method.
bhagwandas armani: Okay, structure output, okay.
bhagwandas armani: Okay.
bhagwandas armani: We discussed that, right? And these are all… yeah, I remember now. I can relate to that. Okay, I can relate to that now. And these are all deterministic or non-deterministic, maybe it's a very good question.
bhagwandas armani: Good choice.
bhagwandas armani: The whatever we are discussing, the langgraphies, are deterministic flows or non-deterministic flows?
Sunny: Some dynamic, some of the deterministic, like continuous sequential chaining, this is a… not deterministic. Conditional one, it's a, like, dynamic one, okay? Narendra, again, this Sand API, it's a dynamic example.
Sunny: Okay.
bhagwandas armani: Okay.
Sunny: And the tool calling, again, it's a dynamic example, the conditional one, okay. So, it's a… the dynamic, some of the dynamics, some of the deterministic.
bhagwandas armani: Okay, and my last question was, how do we maintain a state if a… I mean, like, if you have a… generally, how many steps you see? Maybe if there are 10 steps, okay, then if 3 steps are completed in a Z1, and there is a failover happen, can…
bhagwandas armani: how can we proceed to make the remaining 7 steps to run on the other AC, basically?
bhagwandas armani: How can we do that?
Sunny: You are seeing, the, lang graph?
Sunny: Let's say we have a multiple step, but it's going to be fair at any step.
bhagwandas armani: Yeah.
Sunny: Then how it will continue the other step?
bhagwandas armani: Exactly, yeah.
Sunny: Yeah, so in that case, now, what you can do… so, you are asking on the infrastructure level, this one, or on a graph level, this one?
bhagwandas armani: How… however we can address it. I mean, more… which is a better way to address that, okay?
Sunny: Hmm.
bhagwandas armani: That's all I'm talking about.
Sunny: So, we… see, if we are talking on the app instance level, right, the… let's say we are running application, the Kubernetes pods, right? So, let's say we are running it over the one first pod, and if it is going to be failed somewhere, right? So…
Sunny: We have another instance. This, basically, instance is, like, sharing our checkpoints, right?
Sunny: shared checkpointer. This… this detail we can pass to the another instance, and it is… it will be having the same thread ID, same thread ID, okay? Whatever, basically, we had to the first instance. And from there itself, it can load the… load the safe checkpoint, and it can continue the process, okay?
bhagwandas armani: Okay, do langgraph does a checkpointing by automatically, or do we have to implement it?
Sunny: Yeah, I do the checkpoint. I think I taught you that in the previous class, you can see.
bhagwandas armani: Yes, I checkpointing, now I can relate it, how we can use checkpointing, okay?
Sunny: Yo.
bhagwandas armani: Got it. Okay.
Sunny: Noted.
bhagwandas armani: Great, thank you.
Sunny: Okay. Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, Rago, what's your doubt? Lokesh is saying, can I go first?
Sunny: Yeah, Lokeshw Smith… guys, anyone is there, please go ahead.
raghu.pr: maximum.
raghu.pr: Asuni, am I audible?
Sunny: Yeah, you're audible, Raun.
raghu.pr: What the ?
raghu.pr: I have just one, doubt. Like, for example, if you have a flow like user, planner agent, research agent, writer agent, and reviewer agent, normally the flow is, like, a sequential one.
raghu.pr: What if…
raghu.pr: Review,
raghu.pr: what if reviewer says something is wrong? How can we send it back to the researcher again? Should we have to use, conditional agent over there, or, like, supervisor agent? Like, how the flow we should think?
raghu.pr: Better flow.
Sunny: Oh, you can put the evaluator or something, no, in that case.
raghu.pr: Okay, like, before,
raghu.pr: Like, checking which one is better. Is it supervisor or conditional edge? We need to do the… evaluation.
Sunny: Yes, yes, yes.
raghu.pr: Sorry for the disturbance.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, yes, right, you are right.
raghu.pr: Okay, so…
Sunny: You can put some sort of evaluator, it can check, and according to that, you can pass it.
raghu.pr: Sure, sir, yeah, thank you.
Sunny: Your Lokesh, what's the doubt?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Hi, Sunny.
Sunny: Hello.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Yeah, can I go…
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can go. Next.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, okay. So, Sandeep, one doubt I, maybe you told in the class I missed it. So, in this subgraph, parallel subgraph that you taught, so we are using the send API, right?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Why specifically we are using the send API? Normal states, it's not able to pass.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: I'm sorry.
Sunny: We are using that, yeah, we are using that for running the parallel thread, okay?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay.
Sunny: Yeah.
Sunny: If we wanted to run the parallel thread, parallel, if you wanted to execute the multiple requests, then we use the send API. Got it?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, so normal graph, also, if we do, we can use the SEND API there as well, if you want to.
Sunny: In any graph, you can integrate that, actually. See, normal graph, basically… normal graph means what? You are saying you.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: I have yours.
Sunny: You will do that, you will do that, basically connectivity, right? And every node is going to be connected parallelly with another node. You will do that particular connectivity, no?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: I mean?
Sunny: Yeah, so you can do, but if the, like, the, let's say, request is so many, okay, me, just thinking that way, the topics, basically, which was coming right now, right? Let's say topic is coming, 100 topics are coming.
Sunny: Okay, on a runtime, 100, 200 topics are coming, then how you will handle that thing? So the SEND API can handle it, actually.
Sunny: Got it.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Lord.
Sunny: You cannot… dynamically, you don't know… see, dynamically, you don't know how many topics will be there, how many topics will be coming.
Sunny: I'm just taking an example of the topic, it could be anything. Let's you build one research application.
Sunny: Okay, you don't know how many topics will be coming in a runtime, and parallel, you have to do the research of it.
Sunny: Okay, you cannot create the aesthetic graph for that.
Sunny: You will have to take a help of this kind of thread and all, alright?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Excellent.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, understood. Also, Sunny, I had sent you my resume last week. Did you get.
Sunny: Yeah, I've seen that, I've seen that, I'll reply back, okay?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, thanks. A few more doubts I have, actually. I attended one interview this week.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: I got one question, I don't know what is this answer for this, actually. Interviewer asked, how can LLM identify invisible or hidden text?
Sunny: Sorry, I did not get…
SUSMIT BANERJEE: How can an LLM identify invisible or hidden text?
Sunny: How Adam can identify invalid with hidden tech.
Sunny: From where?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: From, maybe multimodal document or anything.
Sunny: Oh… Hidden text, right? So, C.
Sunny: What kind of document, with respect to what kind of document he was asking?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Actually, I didn't, ask much, told this thing, I really didn't,
SUSMIT BANERJEE: get the answer for this. So, it was a very quick interview, actually. They wanted to…
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Have a very quick one.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Question came, I didn't have any idea how to…
Karthik: I think he's talking about invisible prompts, I mean, if at all…
Karthik: Your prompts, right, for prompt injection, if there are any hidden texts there, so that they can.
Sunny: No, no, actually, now, see, this document also contains some hidden text. Okay. Let's say we're talking about the,
SUSMIT BANERJEE: It is not…
Sunny: Not a docx file. DocX file. So, in the docx, actually, it's always an XML file. So, the docx file, it could be a combination of the visible text, metadata, as well as the hidden text.
Sunny: Okay. Okay.
Sunny: We are going to be converting a DocX document into the XML, so we'll be getting that hidden text. So, this question could be into that context also. So, just ask that context, right? In which context you are asking. If you are saying hidden text, then with respect to what?
Sunny: Okay, so with respect to any document, or LLM is doing a parsing of the document, is trying to understand the layout of the document, the metadata, okay? Or needs to identify any specific character. So, just by giving the instruction, we can do that.
Sunny: So, you should always ask the, like, cross-question over here with respect to what you are asking the hidden text, okay? But my basic understanding is, let's say we have a document, so the document itself is not a document. Behind that, it's going to be maintained one file over, okay?
Sunny: So, I have worked with a docx document, I know better about that. It's going to be maintained one XML file, and it's having a more detail, which we cannot see, inside the document directly, the docx file. Got it?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, another, thing, so, I got some questions on LLM and RAG evaluation metrics, so when we will be covering that in Deep E, where is it?
Sunny: It will cover it. Raga, Deep Evel, this 2 to 3 framework will cover. Okay, I know which framework are being used in the, like, enterprises right now, so I cover those things with respect to those framework, okay? So, just give me 2 to 3 more classes. Let me complete, this,
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, fantastic.
Sunny: And I'll give you some more material, guys, to everyone, so that you can look into the other framework also. I have some comparative material. Whatever thing we have created in the langgraph, let's say if you are using Crew AI, AutoGen, or any other framework, then how you can build the same kind of system. So, I'm not going to explain those things in the classes, but I'll give you those materials, so that at least you can compare from your end. Got it?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Yeah, yeah, sure, sure, take your time.
Sunny: Perfect.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: And last, last one question, sorry. So, Agent Crack, we have all… already done in the class, right?
Sunny: RAG we have done. Agent take RAG is what? Just to use this feedback loop, okay.
Sunny: Just to, like, again, run that pipeline if something is not going to be satisfied, something we are not able to evaluate properly. That's the Agentic rag, I think, right? So we understood everything in the bits and pieces right now, and with that, we can design the Agentic Rag itself. So in the upcoming session, I'll show you, okay?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Okay, fine. And there is also one graph, right?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: That is also graph… graphite.
Sunny: GraphReg, see, I think it is not required, but if you want that, I can provide a solution. One of my videos there on YouTube, you can check out that also. It'll give you the sufficient understanding.
Sunny: Okay, so…
SUSMIT BANERJEE: And then I'll check the.
Sunny: Yeah, you can check.
Sunny: If you want a solution, I can do that.
Sunny: It's just a way of arranging our data, and to retrieve our information from that data, that's it. So we have three ways of arranging our data. One is an embedding one, which we have learned, it's very useful.
Sunny: Most of the time is being used in the industry. Second, non-indexing form, the shallow indexing, which is called the… sorry, which is called the shallow embedding.
Sunny: Okay. And the third one is the graph. So in three-way, basically, we can arrange the data, and we can retrieve the information out of that.
Sunny: Okay, so this, embedding one is a very important and a useful one. Most of the time, we are using in real solutions. Graph is not also bad, but not for every sort of a solution, okay? Just create some complexity.
Sunny: unnecessary complexity in the solution, so it's not always a good, basically, approach. Got it?
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Understood.
SUSMIT BANERJEE: Thank you, Sunny.
Sunny: Think.
Karthik: Yes, Karthiko?
Sunny: Wait, Lokesh, can you speak?
Sunny: I cannot see your number, just raise the hand from that number.
Sunny: 6, 8, or 8, 6.
13098921186: Yeah, please go ahead with the dog.
13098921186: Sir, first of all, how are you?
13098921186: Sorry to, ask.
Sunny: Yeah.
13098921186: Questions yet?
13098921186: Yeah. So, actually, the thing is, like, you know, I just wanted to check with you a couple of things. Right now, in our current, project, we do have an AgentK requirement.
13098921186: So, they are using mainly Databricks here. You know, they wanted to do some kind of, you know, migration things. So, it's like, you know, I think, you know, from having metastore to,
13098921186: So, they are asking us to build an Agentic AIA. So, whatever the knowledge which you have, given, explained to us, is that enough for me to get… to pitch and to take up the task?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can basically develop a solution on the Databricks, okay? See? I am coming up with one project on Databricks on my YouTube, soon it will be uploaded, so you can take a help of that, the complete, Agentic pipeline Databricks, okay?
Sunny: using the Databricks app, Databricks Datalog, Databricks, basically this one, Agentic Flow, sorry, this Databrint Agentic feature, right? And Databricks jobs and all, everything I have included over there. I think 10 video I recorded, 2 more videos there, I'll upload that, okay?
13098921186: Sir, are you going to use Gen AI agents as well there?
Sunny: Yeah, agent only, so whatever agent you are…
13098921186: I mean, building? Yeah, let me tell you there what I see there. There is a one genie…
13098921186: As any AI is there, which will create all the coding part, but along with that.
13098921186: So, they have… Derapix has separate models, like, survey models.
13098921186: they have their own database LLM models, which they're using it right now. So, with that, so, we wanted to create a Genie AI model. Are you going to use the same thing? Ajit, I mean?
13098921186: Jenny, Jenny Agents.
13098921186: Z in the…
Sunny: Ginny, actually, it's not an agent, actually. Ginny, actually, it's a bot which is integrated with Databytes, okay, like Cloud Code, Copilot, and all.
Sunny: So, on top of that, only you are doing some enhancement, is it?
13098921186: No, sir, actually, those ZVA, chatbot we're using, we're trying to create a code.
13098921186: That is, we have already done.
13098921186: Nice to meet you.
Sunny: So it is enough capable. I think I have also used the Genie AI. It is enough capable to create a code and all.
13098921186: Correct, sir, but I… they want specifically their intercept to create a GNEA agent.
Sunny: Hmm.
13098921186: So, we can implement this approach using separate Agentic A approach, but, can we do it with the GVA agents as well? Because
13098921186: You know, if you want to try outside of those things, no, there will be a lot of configuration setup which we need to do, but instead of that, which we can go with the existing GNE agents.
13098921186: That is my…
Sunny: If you can show me the project architecture, something I can help you, maybe.
Sunny: Aww.
13098921186: Yeah, right.
13098921186: I think I can come up with the next class, I can show up this UCX kind of thing. So what they're trying to do is, like, right now.
13098921186: previous environments, whatever they're using, the Spark versions, and as well as Database versions, which they are using. Previously, it was not, Unity Catala supported versions. Previously, it is high Meta-supported versions.
13098921186: Right now, the major boom is, like, you know, they want this code to push it into the M3 catalog system. The reason why they wanted to do is, like, you know, they wanted to deprecate the previous versions.
13098921186: So, in such cases, all the code will go into RDP versions, it will not work. So, that is why they wanted to move this entire code to the Unity Catalog. When they're trying to do this Unity Catalog conversion.
13098921186: So, they wanted to move this code to Unity Catalog, because in order to support the previous, latest versions, they wanted to move this code to Unity Catalog.
13098921186: So, in order to do this one, they're trying to do is, they're using some tool called U6. U6.
13098921186: is the one which they're using it. With that, they wanted to do it. So, in that case, what they're trying to do is they wanted to migrate all the streaming jobs
13098921186: under… normal table jobs and table magician community catalog. While they are doing that.
13098921186: So, they wanted to implement this as a Agentic approach. They wanted to… they are trying to… they are asking us to implement an Agent KA approach, such a way that near future, also, all the… whatever the conversions are there, workspaces, they wanted to go with this approach only.
Sunny: Yeah, you can create MK approach, and you can develop
Sunny: app, you can use the data from the Unity catalog, and,
Sunny: It is possible over the Databricks, okay.
13098921186: Yeah, yeah. So, if at all, if you're creating, let us know in the call tomorrow, if you are creating any YouTube videos, we need to start looking into it, because I have a knowledge, I can do that, but the problem is it's completely client-facing.
13098921186: So, I should not be in a position such as saying that, you know, I am new to this one, if I did any mistake, that is… that will be in trouble to the entire project and company itself. So, it's like, where I'm working in service-based company, there it will be a lot of problems to me. So, that is why I'm not doing the front-facing right now.
Sunny: Okay, okay.
13098921186: Already, they have given me this project, but, you know, they asked me to look into it, but the problem is, I can… I said that I am very much confident in things, but I'm not very much confident in building the Kai, so that is why I wanted to take your solution, so whether I can start doing this.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, so you can practice with this, Agentic flows and all, okay? And the same thing you can.
13098921186: Yeah.
Sunny: you can basically deploy it as a customized application also, which will… which is built in the… this one, langre app, okay? You can do that.
13098921186: Yes.
13098921186: So, with this knowledge, I can go ahead and I can implement it. Even MCP is also not required, right? For this one? Is it required for MCP here? No, right?
Sunny: No, MCP not required, until you're not going to be, like, use a tool-based approach, so it depends on your architecture. Just learn the MCP, you will understand the uses of it, okay? Don't worry.
13098921186: Yeah, yeah. So, I have an idea of MCP, because I have gone through the videos, but not completely in-depth.
13098921186: So, before going to this, take a call, I wanted to take your session, that is why I just… I just talked, I was talking right now with you, yeah.
Sunny: Yeah, okay, after learning that, you will get an understanding.
13098921186: Yeah, thank you for your support. I already… I'm having a clear understanding so far right now.
13098921186: So, I'm very much confident about the things, whatever you dealt so far, because I was able to understand 100%. Thanks for your effort, yeah. Also, please. Yeah, once your notebook is ready, once you're ready with your YouTube, okay?
Sunny: Definitely, sir. Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Sunny: Guys, just give me one minute, okay, wait.
Sunny: Yeah, guys, we're gonna start, so… Yeah, next stop.
Karthik: Es en Karthikono.
Sunny: Yes, you could go ahead, Kante.
Karthik: Yes, so, it may be a very nave question. But, we also, I mean, is that, you know, the, what is that, reactive agents, what we call it, right? A reactive flow. So, is it a part of, the evaluator pattern you, just explained?
Sunny: No, no, it is part of the agent tool pattern.
Karthik: Oh, Asian tool pattern, okay, okay.
Karthik: Agent tooling sense, where a LLM directly calls the tool.
Sunny: Gold. Yeah, correct.
Karthik: Okay, so will there be any other classes based on this, reactive, this thing, or that would be.
Sunny: I think I already thought, if you wanted to, like, build something on top using the React flow, you can utilize that solution, okay?
Karthik: Puck.
Karthik: Okay, sure, sure, sure, that's awesome. Thank you, thank you.
Sunny: Yes.
Krish S: Yes, Sunny?
Sunny: Yes, Raghu or Krish, anyone is there? Guys, go ahead.
Krish S: Yeah, that's Krishna.
Sunny: Yeah, Krish.
Krish S: Sunny, I have a question, like, you know, I think we have come, like, very far along the course, like, almost 50 sessions, what you showed me today. So if I have to prioritize, let's say, for my interview for next 45 days, right?
Sunny: Hmm.
Krish S: like when I say, like, you know, giving really serious interviews with some good companies, how should I go over your material and kind of focus on those key topics? What would be your recommendation or advice?
Sunny: So, my recommendation would be, basically, if you can learn all this topic, okay?
Sunny: So, see, I provided you the handwritten notes, I provided you the, all the solution and all, correct? So, I would suggest you to create one, your handbook of using this material.
Sunny: And read those… read that handbook on a daily basis. 11112222 chapter.
Sunny: Okay. Okay, that's one approach. With that, actually, everything fit in your mind for forever. Got it? The second, basically, if you are asking, Sunny, if I have an interview in the next 30 days, 20 days, or next week, then what topic I need to be learned? The first thing I would suggest to the RAG one.
Sunny: Okay, the second I would suggest to this langgraph Agentic Flow.
Sunny: Then the other subsequent topic, along with the langraph, like, MCP guardrail evaluation, and all the project and the cloud technology and all. So these are the, mandatory ones.
Sunny: or for… before any interview, you can revise all this thing. But my suggestion would be, create your own handbook using this material. You can take a help of the AI over here. So, you can, quickly give all this, detail, as a JIP,
Sunny: to the cloud or chat GPT, as to create one handbook on top of this material, and
Sunny: read that handbook on a daily basis, like you are reading any book, any newspaper, something like that, so this thing will fit in your mind. Because the same approach I took when I was basically new in the data science and the AI field, so I revised the topic multiple times, okay?
Sunny: When I was, like, in the data science first time in 2020, in 21, 5 to 6 years back. So I created my handwritten notes, some book and all, and I was reading the chapter, on a daily basis. Okay, so what happened, actually, after some time, after 5… 5 to 6… 5 to 6 alteration.
Sunny: this automatically went into my mind, okay? And I got a very broader picture of the AI on a high level, and whenever something new comes, I can directly connect to that.
Sunny: Okay. So that's why I'm able to adapt this generative AI in a very quickly manner, and Agentic everything, whatever thing is coming inside the AI world, right? So, if you're going to take that approach, it will help you forever. Got it?
Krish S: Got it, got it. And I guess, you also recommend to supplement those with your, you know, the coding examples that you have shared.
Krish S: Okay, okay. Another quick follow-up question. I see a lot of trend now, like, you know, hardness engineering, loop engineering, and all that stuff, like, primarily around, skills in the cloud and agents in the open AI, right?
Krish S: I don't know if you plan to cover this in depth, but do you have any source where, you know, I can review and probably, you know, get a head start?
Sunny: Sorry, what you said?
Krish S: like, you know, basically learning, like, you know, the cloud skills and, you know, OpenAI agents. Like, similar to cloud skills, they have OpenAI agent skills, right? So, do you have any recommended source that…
Sunny: Yeah, so Claude skill and all, everything will learn here itself, in the live class.
Krish S: Okay.
Sunny: Okay. And if you're talking about the loop engineering, harness engineering, so these terms actually are associated with the Agenticia itself.
Krish S: I see, yep.
Krish S: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, so if you have a grip on this Agent API, then I think you can implement it. So, harness… what is the meaning of the harness engineering? So, harness engineering means what? Like…
Sunny: around to the AI agent to create a complete environment, the execution environment.
Sunny: Okay.
Krish S: Right, right.
Sunny: So let's say we have a LLM, we are going to be connected with the tools, we are building up the memory there, we are exposing the tool via MCP, we have a permission, sandbox, logging, metrics, test, verification, everything. That's called the harness engineering.
Sunny: Okay.
Krish S: Okay.
Sunny: And what is a loop engineering? To run an agent again and again inside the control environment, okay, in the control cycle. So that's a… that's called a loop. So that's… we have already learned, right? Observe, think, act, check results.
Krish S: evaluate.
Sunny: So, feedback loop, evaluate loop, react one, it comes inside of loop engineering already. Got it?
Krish S: Got it, got it. Okay, great, all right. Thanks, Sunny.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you.
dwipal: Listen.
Sunny: Yeah, next round, Deep Pal?
dwipal: Amazing.
Sunny: Or Pokhraj, anyone's their goal.
dwipal: Hi, so, Sunny, I have more than 5 years of experience. I also worked on a rack.
dwipal: I'm applying for interviews, but very rarely I'm getting interview calls.
dwipal: I'm applying on, LinkedIn and, on, Nokkari as well.
dwipal: But…
Sunny: Can you show me your resume?
dwipal: Just a little check.
Sunny: I'm adding on a panelist, please show me the resume.
dwipal: doubt, Arti till then, I will check.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, sure. Yeah, until Pokhraj, you can go ahead.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Hi, hi, Sunny. Thanks, thanks for giving me opportunity. So…
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Basically, Sami, not… some generic question, actually, I have.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Basically, nowadays, that semantic layer ontology, data control plane means how it is used in the industry.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Any… any thought on the…
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Basically, on the finance background, on, bank and all, so how they are leveraging
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: They are anything… Any thought? Because…
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: I think, like, discussion I'm getting that we are also kind of thinking, so…
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: I mean, what is your, view on this? Any… anything?
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: On this bike?
Sunny: Sorry, what you said the la- what was the last word?
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: semantic layer ontology, knowledge graph. Knowledge Graph, I understand, means, where we can use that.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Right? Maybe in the data engineering or data science space, maybe for end-to-end lineage for all the things and all, so that will be, definitely required.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Mainly on the semantic layer, ontology, and data control plane.
Sunny: See, semantically, it is having a broader meaning.
Sunny: Right?
Sunny: Actually, if you're talking about the semantic layer, that meaning could be different, different, right? Different,
Sunny: basically scenario, right? So one meaning is, let's say we have a raw data.
Sunny: Okay? So… What we can do, we can convert our raw data into the business-friendly data.
Sunny: Business-friendly, meaning, correct?
Sunny: So, let's say we have a raw data, like text, amount, customer ID, or let's say any risk score or something. So we can… if we have a semantic score… semantic layer, so we can convert this particular data into some.
Sunny: Meaningful data. Let's say text amount, it is with respect to the transaction. Risk score, it is with respect to the customer risk score. Some, okay, let's say the total amount of data.
Sunny: total amount of, basically, total amount of the transaction, right? So, semantic layer, basically, it converts technical
Sunny: data, data structure into the, like, consistent business concept, or we can say, basically, just a meaningful conversion of any sort of a thing. Let's say I've given the example with the data only. Got it?
Sunny: That could be the meaning of the… Basically, this one, semantic one.
Sunny: Okay. Now, if we're talking about the oncology, so it is related to the relationship.
Sunny: Okay, semantic layer is giving you the…
Sunny: Meaning of that. But oncology, basically, it's giving the relationship inside the data.
Sunny: Okay? So, customer owns the account, it's having a various transaction, customer applies for the loan, and it's having some risk category, something like that. So, that's the oncology, got it?
Sunny: Numbers for not.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Yes, some, practical and what, data control plane? About data control plane?
Sunny: Data control plane, basically… Maybe, like, control the data, govern the data. Okay.
Sunny: You're talking about the governance or the monitoring of the data now, right?
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Yes, yes.
Sunny: Yeah.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Do you have any means practical or industry kind of example where these things are used?
Sunny: I don't have such project directly, but you can implement it in any sort of a project, okay? So, let's say any use cases there.
Sunny: Yeah, you can implement it. Just take any banking-related data, anything, right?
Sunny: And just implement on top of it. Got it? Build a semantic layer oncology, and then this data control panel… plane, sorry.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Okay, Sunny, maybe I will ping you, okay?
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: LinkedIn.
Sunny: Okay.
Pokhraj Chaudhuri: Thank you.
Sunny: Yes, who is showing the resume? Deepal, right?
dwipal: Yeah.
Sunny: Yadaval, so, what… Issue you have with your resumer, let me check.
Sunny: Software engine with Five Gaurav Action We have Development Data Engineering Cloud.
Sunny: For which role you are applying?
dwipal: Yeah, software engineering role, related to AI.
dwipal: like, AI engineering role.
Sunny: Software engineering and AI, two different roles, okay? So, if you're applying with the software engineering with 5 years of
Sunny: Experience, then here only your resume will be, like, rejected, okay.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: You need to be, like, cautioned over here while you're mentioning a summary about your experience.
Sunny: See, if you are applying software engineer as a AI engineer, then there is a new role in a market, FD role, right? So, that covers software engineering along with the AI engineering.
Sunny: Okay, so, in that many will have to be mentioned. So, I would suggest if you are writing software engineering with 5 years of experience, if you are applying for the AI role, then
Sunny: It's difficult.
dwipal: booking.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: Because system… there is automated system, just by reading your summary only, it will reject your resume.
Sunny: So, just mention the strong summary over there. Ai engineer, something like that, with, 5 to 10 year of… sorry, at least 3… 2 to 3 year of experience, okay? Mention 3 year of ex- 2 to 3 years of experience in the AI.
Sunny: And write the AI-specific words over there.
Sunny: Got it?
Sunny: Then, software engineering, you written again the software engineer, I would say, change it with the AI engineer, right?
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: You are doing all the data literacy stuff, ERIS stuff, and you are writing software engineer. Contradictory statement.
Sunny: So, change it.
Sunny: Second experience, scroll down.
Sunny: Software engineer.
Sunny: Okay, this might make sense, because…
Sunny: the Ava experience you can show as an AI engineer.
Sunny: And the below one is a software engineer.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: the help of the AI to review it, this, to revise this resume, review it, just give you your thoughts, whatever I'm saying, modify accordingly. Show me again, okay? Scroll down.
Sunny: Freelancing web developer.
Sunny: So, here I would say, see, actually, what is the problem now here? You have not mentioned your projects.
dwipal: Yeah.
Sunny: to have 5 year of experience, yeah. Five year of experience person is not, like, the, highly experienced, it's, like, intermediate level of expertise, right? You just enter into the, that mid-level of experience right now, because
Sunny: 2 to 3 years of experience, up to 4 years of experience, just like a starting career.
Sunny: 5 to 8 to 10, 11, 10, 10 year of experience, just the intermediate level. Then we come in a different range than the senior roles, right? The director and all. So here, I would suggest you mention about the project work.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, mention about the AI-related project.
Sunny: Your software development-related project, whatever work you have done.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: Mentioned the specific use case.
Sunny: Just create one more page. Two pages of resume is fine.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, summary, correct the summary.
Sunny: just, like, what I would say, write the skill set.
Sunny: After the summary, AI relevant skill set.
Sunny: Then, write the professional experience, if we can conclude it within 3 to 4 lines, each, with each.
Sunny: And then mention at least 3 projects.
Sunny: Okay?
Sunny: Or else, in the professional experience itself, just remove all this description, write the project there.
Sunny: Got it. We'll operate the project.
Sunny: How you can divide the project? First, write the company name, write the duration of the project.
Sunny: for which problem statement you have solved… which problem statement you have solved, how did you solve that, and what was the tech stack was used over there. So, define the project in this way. Got it?
Sunny: Then start applying for the job and see what is our response. If it does not come, then again, we'll take a different way, okay?
dwipal: And, should I mention data engineering-related project, or just software engineering and AI-related projects only?
Sunny: If you are applying for the AI-related project, then why are you mentioning the data engineering-related project?
dwipal: We, I saw that, RAG for RAG, data pipelines.
dwipal: We do data cleaning and data.
Sunny: Data pipeline is not your work. Okay.
Sunny: Till some extent, you can do that, but the typical data pipeline
Sunny: Okay, you are not going to be billed until you are not only the one there, right?
dwipal: So…
Sunny: don't consider that work as a data engineering work. Say, I have done some preliminary work also inside the AI, along with the AI. I build the proper data pipeline, I use the AI over there.
Sunny: Okay? Say AI everywhere, in a data pipeline also. Say I've built a user AI over there, and the parsing technique also I have used, got it.
Sunny: So, just say in that way.
Sunny: Agustro.
dwipal: And,
dwipal: It means, after 5 years of experience, do companies, only check, technical knowledge or leadership?
dwipal: Kind of.
Sunny: So, see, it depends on company, again.
dwipal: Work took a shift.
dwipal: Your projects are kind of thing.
Sunny: See, it depends on company.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: If you're going for any product-based company.
Sunny: Let's say for giving an interview in Uber.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: Let's see if you're giving an interview on Amazon.
Sunny: Those companies will ask you the DSA and the programming-related question for sure.
Sunny: Recently, one of my friends got selected Amazon.
Sunny: I asked the interview process with him, so he was saying, yes, there was the data structure, and he was preparing the data structure from the beginning of his career, means from 3 to 4, from past 3 to 4 year itself.
Sunny: Okay.
Sunny: So, in those.
dwipal: A lot of these data stuff, they are related. I'm asking about leadership,
dwipal: Do they check, if I have taken any leadership Tim…
Sunny: Leadership also? See, leadership, again, they won't ask you much about that, because…
Sunny: as a 5 to 6 year of experience, they won't give you the leadership role, okay? In the big enterprise, in the big GCCs, they don't give that, generally.
Sunny: So, you might be joined as a senior associate, where you will be doing as a development-related activity only.
Sunny: So, leadership-related question, no, they will not ask you, yeah, but some generic question, they might ask you, let's say, if any…
Sunny: like, manager, leader, or director is connecting with you as a last round, right? So, in the last round. So, he can ask you, okay, in which project you were, what was your role there? Okay, if you're getting, 3-4%, like, how you will manage in your project, if you're trying… if you're going to be lead this project. So, some generic question.
Sunny: Okay, so with your… with your understanding, you can answer those questions. Got it? So let's say tomorrow he's asking to you, okay, Deepal, so you were working in the project, how many people were there in the project? What was your role? Okay, tomorrow you are going to be handle this project, going to be lead this project, you are going to be own this project. Now, how you will manage that?
Sunny: So, this kind of question, my task, right? Not the complete leadership and all the stakeholder, this, that, not like that, okay? Mainly, you're doing a development activity with this experience, got it?
dwipal: Okay.
dwipal: And one last question, I'm currently applying on LinkedIn and on, Nokari.
Sunny: Hmm.
dwipal: Could I focus on these platforms only, or…
dwipal: What kind of…
Sunny: I have… when I applied for the jobs, right? So, I applied via LinkedIn. We got a resp… we get a response from there, from the NOCRI also. But, see, I took another approach also. I always try the referrals, okay? So, I asked to the people if someone can refer me directly.
Sunny: With that, actually, I directly get the interview calls. So, that approach works.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: Okay, if you have connects, any of your… any of your friend, or any colleague, any, like, well-known person is working in the industry, right? If you have, like, friendship or something, then ask to him.
dwipal: Okay, okay.
Sunny: Okay, just ask for the… On this one, referral.
Sunny: Anywhere, right?
Sunny: See, the consultancy, it's a little easy.
Sunny: Crack a job compared to any other product-based startup.
dwipal: Okay.
Sunny: I would suggest you, you can try out with that.
Sunny: If you're any of your friends in Ewoge, Deloitte, or any and any other company, right? So they're the openings on a daily basis.
Sunny: Any of the team is hiring Agent DeKa engineer, or many of the team hiring is the genre engineer, right?
Sunny: So, interview process is also not very tough, so you can try out in that way. Got it?
dwipal: Okay.
dwipal: Thank you.
Sunny: Yeah, thank you, Deepal. Now, next doubt, any more person having doubt?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Yeah, I'm, I'm old speaking.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Hey, buddy.
Sunny: Yeah, you're ordering.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I had one, question regarding the, the API, API pricing. So, for example, we discussed about that, use case, etc. So.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I mean, when we go to the OpenAI pricing page, it… I mean, for example, for the coding… for just for the coding, part, suppose if we want to build some coding agent or coding rack, something,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: then, I mean, like, GPD 5.6, this, Luna model also is sufficient, and it's given that, for the million tokens, it is required, like, it charges about
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: For input, $12, and for output, it's, like, around one word. So, my question is, like,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Is this the actual pricing, or because when we… we often hear that,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I mean, the, like, AI is very costly and those things. So, is this pricing final pricing, or there are a lot of overlays apart from this?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: When we, as compared… as for example, if you're building a RAC solution, or maybe, a GenAI solution.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So, I mean, I want to understand that, because, like, we had heard, like, recently that, I mean, some companies, the complete, like, the quota for the year was consumed in 3 months itself, and those things.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So, I mean, because I don't have any tactical experience regarding this, so…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: But suppose if I want to implement some project, or maybe make a recommendation of a project.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: then, need your, like, need your insight regarding the pricing of this Lakra. Do these API, these pages, the, OpenAI pricing page, is that the final pricing, the… because I mentioned, like, 1 million tokens is a huge amount, right?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: 1 million topos, even if they are charging… for higher models, they are charging, like, suppose 5.6, SOLD is charging, they're charging $4, for the input.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: For one million.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So, is this final pricing, or there is additional pricing?
Sunny: See, you are asking whatever model is telling the pricing, right? So, whatever model is showing now, just check…
Sunny: Is it of inferencing price?
Sunny: Okay? So the token pricing, actually, is just an inferencing price.
Sunny: Okay, in that, two things comes. One, basically, is the input token, and second is the output token.
Sunny: Okay.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Good night.
Sunny: both pricing could be different. How many tokens you are providing, and how many token is being… after processing, what is the output number of token.
Sunny: Got it? For the total cost, whenever you're going to be calculating the total cost, right? So it could be the different one. So how it could be the different one? Let's say you have built an application.
Sunny: So, total cost equal to the LLM cost means the inferencing cost, means the input and output, correct? Then, the second is the embedding cost, vector DB cost.
Sunny: application server cost, storage cost, API gateway cost, if you're using any observability and traceability tool, that cost, right?
Sunny: Security infrastructure, that cost, data infrastructure, that cost, so…
Sunny: Production cost is something different, but if you're talking about the LLM token count, so just inferencing whatever input token you are providing, whatever output token you are getting, it is cost around to that only. That's it.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, so suppose if you're building just a kind of,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: a kind of proof of concept, then… I mean, then just the token, then the pricing mentioned in the… in the pricing page is approximately, we can take that, just for the proof of concept. But the actual, when it goes into the production, then the, other infrastructure cost will come into, the check, right?
Sunny: Correct. Right.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, so… So the… okay, okay, okay.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, fine. Okay, so there are… so, I mean, the other infrastructure, they are completely… there are, some distinct vendors that… they don't have anything to do with the OpenAI or those things, right? For example, the vector AP or those things.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Got it, got it. Okay, okay.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, fine, fine, fine, Sunny. But for the API, but if we just take this, if we are just concerning regarding the actual token cost for programmatically accessing the APIs through, suppose, at organization level as well, then…
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: The pricing which is mentioned in the OpenAI developer's, project page, that is the… that is the actual project, there's nothing known for…
Sunny: Cheers, cheers.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, okay. So, for the million tokens, that is correct, right?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: The credit is.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: And the token calculation is as per the OpenAI page as well, right? Which is in which they show how they tokenize the text.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Some words, subwords, and those things, right?
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, you can explore that, right?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, okay.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, fine, fine, okay. So, and apart from this, so,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: And one more thing I wanted to ask. So, do you know that, I mean, do you have any confirmation that currently, suppose this GPT6 Astra model is diagnosed, is it able to completely produce, like, Power BI reports from scratch or something like that? I mean, do you have information regarding that?
Sunny: No, I have not used regarding the Power BI. Just check it out.
Sunny: poor ones.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, because they mentioned that we need to install some plugins for it to access it, because, I mean, in that model they have mentioned it is able to take over control of our complete system, right?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: I mean,
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: So, I mean, so in that sense, like, is it for… so my disposal, my… I was just curious whether it is able to
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Which, when they say that, it can take over control of the complete, complete system, so is it able to completely create such, advanced, maybe, Tableau, or maybe a Power BI, like, like.
Sunny: Yeah, yeah, it can do that, it can do that. If you're giving access of a system of that specific platform, it can do that, okay?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay. I mean, if you have installed, if you have it installed in the local, then it can take control of our, system, and it can try, okay.
Sunny: You will have to install the desktop version of it, okay?
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Yeah, yeah, I'm in the codex, okay, fine.
AMOL SANTARAM JAMKAR: Okay, fine, thank you.
Sunny: Thank you.
Sunny: Well, we…